English Subtitle By Riyangans
Instagram: @riyangans_subb
Huh?
Hm.
Stuart.
Illumination!
Phil, Ron, Ralph, stay tuned.
Okay, okay.
Hm.
Okay. Our target is Maxime Le Mal,
Which the Active Catchers of Charge
must catch.
And believe me, a nasty little guy.
So, there is no room for error.
Got it?
Si, boss.
O. Phil, Ron!
Huh?
-Looka. Looka!
Come here, come here!
Jello!
Help me, help me!
Huppa!
- Help me!
- Hm, yummy.
Children can be cruel,
but Maxime is even more cruel.
So, so, so. Look who's there.
There we have Gruser the Loser.
So, there you have Maxime Le Mal.
You look...
Magnificent out? Yes, I know.
What did you think? That I would look like
like a bald loser with a beer belly?
Oops, way ahead of me, non?
-Well...
Oeeeeeh.
Ugh.
Laughter is fun, non?
Well, do you remember
my friend, Valentina?
She was captain
of the Femme Fatale cheerleaders
and the most popular girl
of the school.
Yes, I know.
Nice to see you, Valentina.
Hmpf.
What am I hearing, Gru?
All your dreams of becoming famous
as a villain, which went ... poof-poof?
I don't know if you know,
but I managed to steal the moon.
Really? You mean that moon?
Is it on?
May I have your attention please?
Good evening and welcome,
former students of Lycée Pas Bon.
We kick off the festivities
with the announcement of the winner
Of our coveted trophy:
The Golden Former Pupil.
And now, I no longer beat around the bush.
This year's winner
of The Golden Former Apprentice is....
Um... Oh!
My favorite student, Maxime Le Mal.
What, but you can't do that, can you?
-Thank you, thank you.
Merci, merci beaucoup.
Non, there's really no need.
Oh, thank you. Thank you... Thank you.
You guys probably already know.
I have something very big in the works right now.
You know, there was laughter, because as a
kid was always dealing with cockroaches.
But I soon saw that cockroaches
are a miracle of evolution.
Wow. Wow.
And I am now able
to harness the power and the speed.
And the... What is the word?
The implacability of
the most powerful being in the world.
And that makes me indestructible
and unstoppable!
Maxime, Maxime, Maxime.
Behold the powers of the cockroach.
Oh, oh stop. Stop!
And sad boyfriend of mine,
what do you have to say to this?
Well, I say you...
have been arrested
On behalf of the Active Catchers of Charge!
I didn't think so, mon ami.
-O no? Slime grenade.
Oh.
Hops.
Ho, ha.
Coming in.
Stay where you are!
Huh, Huh.
Haaa.
Stay put.
Halt!
Got it.
Non, non, non. Non.
Surely this is impossible. C'est impossible.
Hands off me, all of you.
I command you to let go of me.
Goodbye, Maxime.
Who's the loser now?
Loser, loser, loser.
Aaaaah!
This is not over!
You can't let the AVL
out in front of you, coward.
Mark my words.
I'm going to exterminate you, Gru.
What...
Um, not creepy, mind you.
Hello, everyone.
Gru, what's up?
Yay, Gru.
I'm so glad you're here.
-Everything kits at the Gru-tjes?
Look what I taught Guit.
Guitje, sit.
Oh Guitje, I said "sit.
Well, he's only had
had one lesson, mind you.
Maybe we should
practice outside from now on.
There's my darling husband.
Did you bring milk too?
Yes indeed, they had all sorts of things. Almond milk,
soy milk, hemp milk, oat milk,
goat milk, chocolate milk, coconut milk,
powdered milk and I have cleansing milk.
Do you also have regular milk?
-No, they don't make that anymore.
Ho.
Wait a minute.
One, two, three girls, one woman....
So something is missing.
-No, I believe we are complete. Yup.
Or for that matter? I'm forgetting something. This one here!
That's my boy. There he is.
Where is daddy's kiss?
Oh, who's a little cranky here?
Even though you are a sourpuss,
you love your daddy.
Go on. Say: Daddy. Daddy.
Of course he loves you, but
he doesn't show it on his face.
Or with his body language.
Right, Gru Junior? Come on, show daddy
how much you love him.
Oh, I do know what makes you happy.
Hmmm, Bahama stew.
No. It's from the Bahamas,
very far away. Look, oh, so yummy.
That really has a Caribbean vibe.
See? He loves his daddy.
He shares it.
Phil, Ralph, Ron.
Brushing briefly.
Polishing.
Thanks, guys.
Rattle bum?
Bips.
I need to have a word with you.
-Sure, but...
There is no time for chatter.
Maxime Le Mal sent a message
sent from his cell.
Bonjour, Gru.
I know you're listening, so listen.
You think you can humiliate me?
And get away with it? Yes?
So don't. If I escape
escape, I will come and take revenge on you, Gru.
But this time I will
not be gentle with you.
And I know where you live.
So I would just sleep with one eye open,
because you can't hide.
Sleep tight, Gruser.
Don't worry, he can't get out of there anyway.
It's a very heavily guarded prison.
Ah, yes, well, um....
He escaped yesterday.
-What?
Out of our house?
Oh no, you think that's super.
It's called a safe house.
And that's fun. And that's safe.
And that's great. And we're going.
You are getting a new room
And a new school.
That will be fun, right?
Everything all new. Nice.
What about my friends?
You do make new ones.
Probably better ones.
Unbelievable.
Yes yes, lots of emotions, different life.
No weeping, hup with those legs.
Go ahead, come on.
I'm so sorry
That you can't come with me, Guitje.
Are you taking good care of him?
Be nice, Guitje.
Don't forget to practice your tricks.
We will be in a few hours
at the safe house.
Mayflower is a lovely little town.
A lovely, safe and boring town.
Believe me, this is the best, Gru.
What about grandma? What about Uncle Dru?
Sorry, no one can know
where you are.
Not even the family.
-Every disadvantage has its advantage.
You promise to
take care of the other Minions?
Those are sitting high and dry
in the AVL headquarters.
I have big plans for them.
Well, good luck with that.
Now enough is enough!
Silence!
You are now on Carl's bus.
And Karl is a longtime employee
at the AVL,
Who wants to reach retirement age
wants to reach.
So here in Karl's bus
you stick to Karl's rules.
No mischief, no shenanigans,
no old-boy crap.
Currant bread?
So this stops.
Or you will be introduced to a side
of Karl that you don't want to know.
Is that clear, gentlemen?
Bazooka!
Karl doesn't like this. Hands off.
What are you doing? Don't squeeze! No, no!
We are here.
The town of Mayflower.
This safe house has been used for years
to protect our agents.
Oh, look at that.
Wow, those lawns, those flowers!
- Wow, that's cool.
- Are we literally going to live here?
Look at that fountain.
-Wow. Fat cool.
- Oooh, oooh, is that our house?
- Oh, look at that!
- Oh, how beautiful!
- I could get used to this.
It looks like there
a princess lives there.
And here it is.
Your new home.
O.
No fountain.
-I'm sure it will be fun here.
Come on.
According to Silas, there is a swimming pool
in the garden. Now that's fun, isn't it?
Wow, it's so cold and unsociable.
But in a homely way.
Yes, it is according to the standards
of the AVL set up.
Little comfort, but a generous enough
for functionality.
There is even an automatic
emergency lock. Isn't that fun?
Ow, an emergency lock.
Yippee.
It has a candy machine.
Too crazy this house!
See.
Ouch.
Hoppa.
-Ha.
This is going to be great.
-Beautiful, and now to the point.
For your safety,
you will be given a new identity.
Do we really need them then?
-No discussion possible, Gru.
Well, you are a salesman
of solar panels.
Lucy, you're a hair stylist
in an upscale hair salon.
A hair stylist? Yes, jackpot.
Did you pick that because I cut my own
hair cut and I'm going to flame in this?
No.
Chet Cunningham?
Ah, that actually sounds nice.
Girls.
Cool, I'm Beril.
Britney?
-My name is Brie?
Oh come on, there are worse names.
-Yes, like Bea.
Yes, Margot. Bea, what a terrible name.
How sad if your name is Bea.
Really, I don't know a worse name....
My name is Bea, isn't it?
Yep.
Well, that takes some getting used to.
You girls go pick out a room
pick a room, and I'll talk to your parents.
Yes, I didn't want to scare the girls,
but it is vitally important
that you keep your identities secret.
Gru, I have to ask you,
please don't be Gru-ish.
What do you mean by that?
I'm just saying that you often stand out
in a crowd and no more.
You know. Um... Like when you're
cranky and irritable.
And if you make it a little uncomfortable
for everybody.
Yes, you do.
I mean, you know...
-Okay, enough.
I don't make people
feel uncomfortable.
I comfort all people,
just like a plum cake.
I am quite manageable.
This is not uncomfortable.
You are making it uncomfortable.
Gru, you must not stand out. Your family
is in mortal danger. Do you understand?
Sure, yes. We understand that. We do
everything for the safety of our family.
Right, beautiful. I'll be in touch
when everything is over.
Until then, bringing in
of Maxime Le Mal is our top priority.
Stay safe.
You know, maybe this is
not so bad.
No chasing villains
or dangerous missions, right?
We can be an ordinary family.
And then I finally get to
to some quality time with the baby.
This is going to be really great. Right, buddy?
Who grabs your nose? Who...
He grabs my nose.
Ouch.
He can squeeze hard. That kid is strong.
Ah.
Thanks. Need to see you guys.
We're having fun, right?
I love you guys.
Thank you, my wonderful army.
Maxime is back, yes!
A special merci beaucoup to those who
helped me escape from the AVL prison.
Tom and Linda, where are you?
Yes, distracting the guards....
Oh, très magnifique.
Now silence!
We make Gru pay for my arrest.
And what better way to do that than by
kidnapping his precious little baby.
Oh, I want to have that baby.
Oh, Maxime.
-Non, non, wait, wait.
Not Maxime. You'll call me
Cockroach Man from now on, huh?
Seems a little obvious,
but it's very obvious. Cool, isn't it?
I won't call you by that stupid name,
but I am so in favor of this vicious plan.
Well, Gru asked. He humiliated me
humiliated me and in front of the whole school.
I had my trophy and all that stuff.
But now the game begins.
He may run away like the mouse,
but we find him like the cat.
Game on.
Stop.
Stop!
Okay, here are Chet's scrambled eggs
nice and full of cheese.
And Bea's famous bacon,
that spell your name.
Please, Britney.
Wait. I can't say my
Britney's name. Because then I would be joking.
Yes.
But we are not allowed to jockey at all.
You shouldn't think of it as jockeying.
Just think of it as a form of pretending.
Oh no, I don't.
Ah, a little white lie.
-No.
Agnes, I am your father
And I command you to jockey.
No.
-Yes, joking.
You are treading on thin ice, young lady.
Hmm.
Why don't you look more
like your sister, Edith? That one jokes all the time.
I don't.
-See? See? Now she's joking again.
And well too, I must say.
Okay, this is our first day
at Mayflower.
And as far as I'm concerned, this is going to be a great
day. Right, Chet Junior?
Woohoe! Mayflower, yoo-hoo!
We're going to be late for karate.
-You have to take Margot to school.
- Yippee.
- It must be cool.
Hey, you just have to dare to be yourself
and then Mayflower will take Chet Cunningham
into his heart.
They're going to love him as much
as I do.
And you, little man, you're going to have so much fun
with your daddy.
Mom.
Yep, just you and Dad.
Come on, say it then. Dad.
Dad.
Yes, this will be a fun day.
Hup, hup, hup, hup.
Huppakee.
Okay.
No, go!
Thank you, guys.
Baby.
-Hup, check, chok, chik, check, check, yes.
- All right, thank you, doll.
- Hi huh!
Look, Margot. The neighbors.
Hello!
-Hm?
Come with me. You can do this, Chet.
Your new neighbor, Chet Cunningham.
Uhuh, Perry Prescott.
What brought you here, Chet?
Well...
Um...
Solar panels. Yes, that!
I sell solar panels.
Are you already participating in the solar revolution?
Yes, no. I am already provided for.
Good to know.
And what do you actually do, Perry?
I have Prescott Motors,
the largest car dealer in the state.
Wow, impressive.
This is my daughter Margot.
-Brie, Dad.
Ah, yes.
Yes, did I say Margot?
How funny, because I was thinking....
I thought of a fish
I had as a child named Margot.
He lived in the pond and he died.
Um...
Anyway...
Um... I'm about to take Brie to
school for her first day.
Yeah, I was just about to take
to school, so...
Poppy? Hello, Poppy.
What a nice name that is.
Would you like to carpool with us?
-No.
You can become friends with Brie.
Right? You don't have any friends at all.
Well, nice banter, Chet,
but she has school
and I go with some friends
of mine to the tennis club.
Oe, tennis club. That sounds like fun!
If I were to be invited
To a tennis club,
Then I would love that.
Yes ... Well, we really have to get going now,
so nice knowing you, Chet.
Yes, fun chatting! If you ever want to
want to do, we can just chat!
He does start chatting.
-That was painful.
Just watch, by this afternoon you will have forgotten
who your old, rotten friends were.
Mm, I'm not so sure about that yet.
Really isn't it? Oh my gosh.
Not my problem, bro.
Hey honey, you can do this.
You are smart. You're funny.
You don't have to worry, right?
They're going to like you.
Thank you, Gru.
Bye bye.
Oh, let them like you.
Hi, Poppy.
Um...
Huh?
Drive!
-Sorry, mistake. I'm already going.
Okay, I'm going already!
Ugh, buttocks.
Huh?
All right, gentlemen. Arise.
You may be wondering
What you are doing here.
Um, sí.
As you may or may not know,
I had to interrupt my retirement
to lead the project of the
AVL to deal with Maxime Le Mal.
And that is why you are here.
I'm looking for volunteers.
I need the strongest, the heftiest.
-O.
The fearless.
-Nope.
I look for the best of the best.
So, which one of you will it be?
Yes, very good, gentlemen.
Huh?
The AVL is known
for high-tech weapons and vehicles.
But now we are also developing
high-tech agents.
And I can't imagine better test animals
than you.
Test animals, yes!
You are the first ones
to test our super serum.
Designed to turn you into
top agents with powers and abilities
that those of mere mortals
exceed those of ordinary mortals.
Whether you explode.
We don't know yet.
Um, huh?
Hey.
Yes.
Yes!
O?
Ladies and Gentlemen,
I bring you the Mega Minions.
Cool.
Ah, how cute you guys
looking cute. And very cool and scary.
It would be even better
With a black belt. Hi-yah!
Oh, oh.
I'm going to break a brick with my head.
-That's the way to hear it. Ow.
Okay. Have fun. I'm going to get to work.
Beril and Britney, yes?
-Hm.
Will do.
-Okay, bye, mom.
Day.
Got it.
Hi-yah!
In the circle, people.
Hiyah.
Show respect for your sensei.
-Yes, sensei O'Sullivan.
Hai!
Boscovitch, did I not order you
to cut that hair?
You look like a sheepdog.
-Sorry, sensei.
Well, we have two newcomers today
who want to start their journey
on superness.
You, ukkepuk. Come forward
And tell me your name.
Um...
It's Britney.
What is my name?
You can't.
There is no "can't" in karate.
Ten push-ups after class.
Hey, that's not fair.
How-ha.
I wouldn't be mouthing off
To your sensei.
Hiyah!
Well, are you ready to say
your name and to join in?
Hmm.
I don't think so.
Then sit in the corner
Of shame and reflection
And ask yourself what kind of person you want to be.
Good. Am I gonna have
get in trouble with you?
Yes, probably.
-What do you say?
If you think I don't fight with children
fight, you're in the wrong dojo.
Ha!
Ouch!
That was for my sister.
Huh?
You broke my little toe!
That's going to be a lot of push-ups.
Okay, here comes this.
Hair gel.
Mrs. Cunningham?
-Oh, um, yes, um, hi.
I must say, what a beautiful resume you have.
Oh, what shall I say?
I'm good at what I do.
Well, you are exactly
what we need here.
A lot of demanding divas here
in town.
I'm at a loss for words, folks.
Where is what's-her-name? Renée? Rhonda?
Melora, how sorry I am.
Rachel is on maternity leave.
What, oh, but you just can't do that, can you?
But you're lucky,
because our Bea here is fantastic.
Perfect. I am sitting in my chair.
Okay missy, you may.
And Melora, what are you in the mood for?
What if we wash it
and let it air dry?
Experience the power of nature, or so?
No, I've had that style.
It's time for a whole new Melora.
I want this.
Wow ... Wow.
Um...
Okay, we'll start with the color?
Yes, the color. Because that's where you start.
A little bit of this.
Bit of that.
And-oh, that's beautiful.
This is not so difficult.
Um...
What?
Is it supposed to smoke?
-Yes, smoking means it works.
Huh?
What happens?
-Perfect. Don't panic.
Call the fire department!
Walk, walk, walk.
O.
Where do those go?
Voilà!
My latest creation.
All my transformation powers
in one handheld design, lol.
Oh, it's beautiful. And look at
see that little antenna! That is so cute.
It's not supposed to be cute, non.
I'm going for intimidating.
Terrifying even.
Now all I have to do is
looking for that walking potato
And his baby is mine!
Check this out here.
Wow.
No, this is not a joke.
Really, these people here ... Whoa!
Oh, this is really going to be top notch!
Okay, Daddy is just completely exhausted.
Your diaper is changed. You have your bottle.
Your pacifier.
And here are your balloons.
Look at that, you like those, don't you?
Huh huh, a moment to myself.
Hmm.
They put a glitter bomb
in my locker.
Adolescents are terrible.
Yes...
Babies are no fun either.
Junior!
Ah, okay, okay.
Dua Lipa prosciutto.
Book coverage!
Puste, Ralph.
- Hello, Gru.
- Hello.
What, what? Um, what?
Oh, hello, Poppy. Did you perhaps say something?
What, um, no. My name is Chet, by the way.
Chet Cunningham.
Gru? What? What does that even mean?
That you are not good at lying.
Hey, that's not nice.
Ever heard of respect for the elderly?
I have no respect for boomers.
I laugh at them.
Is that sometimes
a joke? Did you get that one from the web?
Wow.
The web? How old are you?
Well, old enough to know
that you are a nasty, little...
Eh?
I would just be careful.
What Oeh...
You have been a master villain.
That's not me.
I don't even look like that.
You obviously have the wrong one in front of you,
because I'm selling...
Um, solar panels.
Oh, don't worry. I'm not going to expose you.
You're going to help me take a crack at it.
We're going to make a plan tomorrow.
-You want to do a squat?
Listen missy, I'm not-
-No, you're listening, old man.
I got you and I swear to you:
there is no mocking me.
Okay, um, yeah well.
But tomorrow is not such a good time.
Bummer for you.
Because this is going to happen.
Unless you want the whole world to know
exactly who you are.
Gru.
What a creep she is.
Bello, bello, thank you!
Yes!
Hey hey, tap it! Tap it!
Oh, thank you!
Yay...
Ah.
Hey, Jiminy!
No problemo!
Huh?
Oh, pfjoew.
Oi.
Thank you.
-O.
Okay, okay, quiet now.
Quiet!
Thank you.
It's time to start training
in the real world.
Liberty, yeah.
And if you do well there,
you will become AVL's new secret weapon.
Hey, pomodoro!
La pomodoro, hey!
Ugh.
I probably won't
no regrets.
Well,
the painter cancelled.
I don't know what...
Good morning, neighbors.
Hello. You're still
me, right Perry?
O!
-No. No, no.
Yoo-hoo!
-Patsy...
Hey, neighbors.
-Patsy.
Hoi-eh, I'm Perry's wife Patsy.
-Oh, I'm Bea and this is Chet.
Hi. Hey, you know, seeing you
standing here like this,
then I get one
of my brilliant ideas.
Perry is looking for tomorrow
a partner for tennis.
I... I don't know. He just
a tennis fanatic.
Not a tennis fanatic?
I am an avid tennis fanatic.
I am Mister Tennis.
It is my favorite
Of all the sports and games.
With a racket like that and with those balls,
so pretty yellow and hairy.
Settled, then. I'll see you two
at the club tomorrow. Toedeloe.
Okay. Toedeloe, that's where we have to go.
And, so you play tennis?
-Yes, yes, I play tennis.
And quite fantastic actually.
Well, at least it used to be at summer camp.
Oh, how good. Here you go.
Okay, bye. Have fun!
Check it out.
Um, okay.
What?
What should... Huh?
Gru. You can't hide, Gru.
Oh, my back. I can't hold it anymore.
How long is this going to last?
Well, this takes as long as it takes.
Mark my words: Gru is not going to win.
This is not the talent show
from the third grade.
Oh, here we go again.
Yes, again yes. It was a decisive
moment. Why don't you let me?
It was on the night of the show.
I had been practicing a song for weeks
from which my classmates
would freak out.
I wanted to stand up. Then...
What?
...I heard it.
What Oh.
There stood that little jerk
And he did my big number.
He had ruined everything.
I couldn't go on after him.
Then I would have been a fool.
Like I was imitating him.
Maybe it was purely coincidental.
It was just a popular song.
Oh, non, non, non. He knew it.
He did it on purpose.
He loved
to humiliate me.
What now?
-Fuel has run out.
There is always something. Why can't I ever
just be nice and bad?
Okay, parking.
Okay, let's see. Just unleaded.
Oe, wow, that's pretty pricey, non.
Okay, enter pass and quickly delete.
Pass unreadable?
Ah, come on.
Did you remove it quickly, though?
-Yes, yes, it could hardly be any faster.
Hey, bring me a slush.
It's my slush day.
You there. Your stupid device
won't read my card.
Did you remove it quickly?
-Yes.
Well, some do it too fast.
You just have to try again.
I don't have time for this!
Okay, wait!
I am trying to destroy my enemy!
So give me 3000 liters on pump four,
fool.
Please, don't hurt me.
-O, but I'm not going to hurt you.
What?
O.
Look at you.
Much better.
And give me a purple slush, you.
I'm not paying for that,
just so you know. Lekker puh.
Yes, I am that bad.
Hm.
Okay, you guys pick
a healthy granola.
This is Guit's favorite muesli.
He hasn't forgotten me, has he? Right?
Oh dear, that's not possible at all.
You play with Guitje and you dress him up
and you have a podcast.
It's absolutely impossible that he's
forget you. His best friend.
Thanks, Mom.
Look, this one has extra marshmallows.
-Double sugared chocolate lumps.
Yes, we'll take those.
Okay, what else do we need?
Oh no.
She didn't see anything.
She didn't notice anything.
- What is it?
- Huh?
Oh, nothing at all. Just, um, stretching,
before we move on.
Grocery shopping is the cause of
muscle injuries. Didn't know that, did you?
Okay, stretched. Let's go.
Hup hup. Hup, hup, hup.
Okay, the coast is clear...
O.
You.
You did this. Cheater.
Come, girls.
Cleaning crew, aisle nine.
Have always wanted to say.
We are hiding here.
What does the madam want from us?
-Madam? No ma'am seen.
Madam!
Come on. Get out of here. Faster!
Wow.
You are not a hairdresser.
I'm on to you.
Come back, you.
-I have to get out of here.
Okay.
Come back, you.
A, ah o.
Ha.
-Ho.
- Yoo-hoo!
- Hey, no, no, no.
You can't just...
Open, open, open!
Wow.
We go.
Stop. Come here, you.
That was in the nick of time. Always fun
when shopping with Mom.
- You can't do better shopping!
- Now that's life!
Perfecto.
Poppy.
I don't see her, Junior.
-Bove you, smartass.
You are too late.
How do I get up there?
-With the trampoline.
Huh?
Here we go.
Au, au, au, au, au.
Here I am, Poppy Prescott, villainess.
Take a seat, Gru.
-Okay, I'll take...
Okay.
Okay, why am I here?
Because, like you,
I am a born rogue.
And now we need to talk
about our squat.
Crack, please. You are only a child.
Great villains start early.
Didn't you steal the crown jewels
at age twelve?
I was a lot younger than that.
Sorry, but you are not me.
I will most likely be
much better than you.
Check this out here.
Hey, is that my old school?
-Bingo.
Which I expertly recreated
with glue and popsicle sticks.
And what we're going to steal there for a while is:
the school mascot.
Do you want to steal Lenny?
-I do.
Lycée Pas Bon was always
my dream school.
And this crack will look so good
in my rogue log.
This is a very bad idea.
Have you ever seen a honey badger?
They are nasty, mean monsters.
They literally eat bees and cobras
at breakfast.
That doesn't do honey badgers any good.
No no, I'm really not going to help you.
Well, that's the pity of blackmail.
You don't really have a choice.
Come along. Come along!
Okay.
O.
Ah. Um, Tim?
Tim, go, go, go.
Chihuahua.
No!
Stronger!
You the best!
Le salami!
-Le salami!
Suppository!
Give here!
Hey, police!
No problemo.
Hi-yah.
Um, piña colada.
Huh?
Help!
Please, can you help me?
-Ah, si, si.
Huppa.
Hey, all good. Ciao.
Huh?
Grease, come on.
-Hey.
Thank you, thank you!
Ugh, a smooch.
A smoochie.
Woah.
O!
Help!
Bazooka!
Oh, um...
Hey hey. Stop, stop. Police.
Ciao bellos.
Because of them my car is wrecked.
-They destroyed the cafe.
- Get out you guys!
- They are destroying everything!
I've had it with superheroes.
-Yes, we grab them.
Get in. O.
Bazooka!
- Boo!
- Yes, off you go.
Gentlemen, our experiment failed.
You are officially sidelined.
Playing outside!
Huh? Um, no?
Wow.
There it is.
The castle, the gargoyles.
Unbelievable that I am here.
Okay.
Come on. Then it's done.
Ron, my equipment.
Voilà.
Don't lose sight of him.
If you need anything, I've got his
bottle, diapers, favorite pacifier....
Hurry up. Come on, come on.
And now we are going to cut the glass
with my...
Diapers? What?
Am I being taken by the nose sometimes?
Motel la piñata!
Hey, guys. Guys. Guys.
Guys, where's that other bag
with my tools?
In le balloon.
Um...
Oops.
What, huh...
Okay, let's see what I have here.
Um...
Come on, come on, come on.
Aha!
Hm, thank you.
Apple egg.
Huh?
That's Mr. Friendly.
Stupid kids.
No, no, no!
I hate my job.
Pfiew.
Ha, ha, ha.
Oh, that's Dr. Destructo.
Just a kid.
There is the original helmet
of Killer Driller.
Come on. Stay with it for a while.
Diaper.
Huppa.
-Yes.
I have to have something that...
Something that I can...
Like this?
Nice.
Yes!
We're in.
-Wait.
No, no, no.
Baby powder.
Yes, si, si, here.
Wow.
You know, the most important thing
in a squat
is that you remain constantly aware
of possible danger.
La, la tiramisu.
- Come here.
- Hey.
Junior. Junior, come back here.
And what are you up to now?
-I'm working on it.
No, don't touch anything.
No, no, no, no, no.
Yes, well done, Junior. Good job.
Oh, he's having fun.
-Yes, too much fun.
Stop.
Here you go, Junior.
Daddy needs to steal a honey badger.
Okay.
I know they keep Lenny
keep here at night.
And if I'm not mistaken, there should be
a hidden switch somewhere.
Aha.
Yes.
Ow.
I'm going to give him this.
When he is knocked out,
we open the cage.
That downy devil
Sleeps like a baby as long as
Okay, he's still asleep.
Mama mia!
Now my leg sleeps.
Hey! Hey!
Gru, what should we do?
No!
Oh, no. I'm ruining our squat.
What?
Who will dare?
Intruders.
Intruders!
Wake up!
No!
What?
Hmm.
Aw.
No. No.
Come on, we have to go.
Ouch! Come on.
Intruders,
you're bullying the wrong principal.
Here we go, come on. Come on.
Hup, hup, hup.
Come on.
Ugh, you won't get away with this!
Prepare for the fury
of Überschlecht.
Ah, baby butt ointment.
Oh no, oh no! Stop, stop, stop!
Oh dear.
Come back again, you. I want my Lenny!
How can we get out of here?
Follow me.
Get in.
Come on, come on, come on!
Mr. Friendly.
I must say: that was without a doubt
the coolest night of my life.
Unbelievable that we succeeded.
I don't deny it, that was pretty fun.
Thanks, Ron.
Whew, o la la.
And thank you, for everything.
Oh, and hey, no worries.
Your secret is safe with me, partner.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Your daddy did quite nicely, didn't he Junior?
Si, si, si, go, go.
Oh hello, Maxime.
How is my favorite pupil doing?
I think you and I are looking
for the same person.
And I know very precisely where he is.
Thank you, director Überschlecht.
We got him.
Valentina, to Mayflower.
My pleasure.
Ah.
Check it out.
Okay, yes. Yes.
It's all coming back.
Oops.
Okay.
See you later.
Say: Bye, Daddy and Mommy.
-Have fun!
Take good care of yourself.
Bye, huh!
-Bye.
Bye!
Hey, Cunninghammetjes.
-Ehm, hey, Poppy.
Our parents have a play date,
which is pretty cute.
I thought you guys might want to
wanted to do?
Oh, yeah, sure. Come on in.
The party can begin, folks.
She's nice.
-Yes, everyone thinks so.
Nice.
And have you ever seen
seen a honey badger?
Wow.
Okay, they don't make a mess of it.
There are my favo new neighbors.
Hi.
Oh, what a cool vibe.
You guys look like a bunch of pros!
Yes, but we are not.
Perry and the boys are waiting for you
on the job.
We set out to find the clubhouse.
And you tell me where you got
got that insane outfit.
To this, Chet.
Hello.
Okay.
Flip, Jip, Chet. Chet, Flip, Jip.
-Hello boys.
Hello.
-How are you, Chet?
Okay.
Chet here is going to show us
how to do it.
Right?
Um... Hmm.
I'll make that guy
complete in.
Okay.
So what?
Okay, here goes.
Huh, you can't be serious.
Okay, okay.
Better?
What!
Huh?
That doesn't count.
And... What?
You can't just...
This is ridiculous.
Hey!
Thank you, Ron.
Hey, no!
Come and get it.
Aw, he's so cute.
-Wow.
This is the funniest doggie of all time.
I'll go.
Oh hello, little girl. Is your daddy home?
Sorry, I'm not allowed
talking to strange people.
I'm not a strange person.
-Well, you do look strange.
O.
Who is there?
I don't know.
But she's old and smells like brussels sprouts.
Okay, I'm coming already.
Oh no. Um...
I'll be right back.
Is there anything I can do for you?
-Well, I hope so.
I am a friend of Gru's.
Well...
There isn't, so...
Oh, never mind, you know.
I'll wait.
Huh? What? No, ouch!
Tell me when you're ready.
Huh?
Hm?
...so instead
it became Maui.
So you understand, Perry and I are no longer
no longer welcome on the island of Oahu.
Honestly.
- Honey...
- Oh, happy.
The children. We have to leave. Now.
Thank you. Bye.
We were discovered.
-What?
Call Silas.
-O no.
Oe, bella.
Nope.
Bazooka!
Gru is in danger.
We have an emergency, folks.
My retirement is officially over.
Collect the Mega Minions.
Huh, Pomodoro!
Huh?
Ha. Pomodoro!
Hey.
Bello, busy bee.
Aw.
Huh?
Pomodoro!
Yeehaa!
Huh?
Pomodoro!
Pomodoro! Yiehaa!
Yippa, yippa!
Huh?
Wow!
Yeah!
Huh, O...
Well...
Your father has been naughty.
Incredibly naughty.
He stole something
That I would like to get back.
Director Überschlecht?
O.
I know you have my Lenny.
So give it back.
Ouch, ouch!
That's actually a very funny story.
-Cup close.
I don't want to hear excuses.
I'm going to teach you a lesson.
Come on, tough guy.
Okay, I'm really not
fight with an old lady.
Oh no?
Well, I'll kick your ass
that you'll remember for a long time.
What?
Address.
Yeah, go!
Girls, watch out. Over here.
Stay low all of you!
Hey. Stop it, lady.
Ah, girls!
Stop it!
-Let go of him.
Take it!
Now we're going to go in there
And look for that baby.
What?
Oh, jackpot, huh.
-Maxime, this is too easy.
Come on, little bébé.
Join Maxime.
Yes, koetsjie, koetsjie....
Ai, Maxime...
You little brat...
Things are swinging for you, little man.
Got it.
Yes!
What?
Wait. Where's the baby? Where's the baby!
Junior?
Lucy!
Go get the baby!
Maxime.
Say au revoir, Gru.
Oh, and don't worry, because he's going to be
very happy with his new daddy.
Look at him.
Oh, he loves his new daddy.
Junior!
Get in.
We have to deliver a baby.
We got him.
O.
Who is going to be a cockroach?
Ouch!
Let go. Those are very sensitive.
You wriggling worm....
Oh.
Iew.
You don't mean that.
You're piping all over my cockpit.
Valentina, bring me
the cockroach ray.
There they are.
I go off on it.
Here we go.
Woah, woah, woah, woah.
What is that?
Hello.
Ah, Gru.
A little closer.
Yes, almost.
Turn them off.
You're doing a great job.
Put it on, partner.
Hey, I don't see anything.
Junior.
Don't worry, Gru. The baby's okay.
See for yourself.
Oh, Junior.
And so now he belongs to me.
Isn't that so, Maxime Junior?
Together we are going to make mischief, mess
kicking. And have so much fun with it.
And the best part is: He hates you.
He really does.
Release my son.
No, I didn't think so.
The fun is really just getting started now.
Look what a coward
your old daddy is, huh?
Huh?
You're going too far, Maxime.
So give me my son.
That's what I said, right? He's my son now.
Huh? Huh...
Ow.
Watch your step, Gru. It's a
thingy. Now if only you could fly, huh?
Release.
This ends now.
Say goodbye to Daddy.
O.
It's okay, Junior. Daddy loves you.
Come back, you. Bad baby.
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
Get off me, brat.
Meet the fury of the...
Hi-yah!
See? Not a scratch.
Huh, what?
Salami!
Pastrami!
Non, non, non, non.
Prosciutto!
What?
Ow, ow, ow. nasty.
Nice try. If I...
Antipasti.
Gru.
-Junior.
Yes!
Unbelievable.
-Are you guys okay?
Dad.
Aw.
O.
My boys.
You know? Today was just
a huge roller coaster of feelings.
Um, Gru?
May we go back home now?
Okay, look at this.
Yay.
Thank you, Dr. Nefario.
As good as new.
No job too small, or too crazy.
Day day.
-Day.
Hey.
Are you okay, honey?
Agnes, there is someone here for you.
Guitje?
Guitje.
Have you been practicing your tricks?
Okay, lying dead.
Yes!
That was...kind of scary.
-Yes. Kind of was.
Guitje.
Hey, I um...
Be right back.
-O. Okay.
I need to take care of something.
-Yes.
See you later, buddy.
Love you, honey.
O.
How are you doing, Maxime?
What do you come here for anyway, Gru?
Make fun of me? Well?
Laugh? No, no, no, I just need
just need to get something off my chest.
And it's about the talent show
from the third grade.
Look ... Honestly ...
I had stolen your song.
-What?
I knew it. I knew it
wasn't a coincidence. Sneaky liar.
And?
-And what?
And where are your excuses?
What will we experience now?
I just gave that one.
Oh, non, non, non. Those were not excuses.
You just wanted to rub it in.
Unbelievable. You picked my song.
I did that to get back at you because
you pulled down my pants at the gala.
And by the way, you could have gone up after me.
It's not my fault you were scared.
You were afraid because I was a topper.
Me afraid? I'll sing you out whenever you want
And with two fingers in your nose.
I would still like to see that.
Wherever, whenever.
Speak up, mon ami.
Oh yes.
Come on.
Yes!
Oh, yeah.
Come on, rock.
Oh yes!
Bello?
Um...
Oh, strudel.
Hoppa. Hoppa.