[woman] Triple-zero,
what is your emergency?
[man] 9-9-9,
what's your emergency?
[woman 2] 9-1-1,
what is your emergency?
[man 2] No one knows
what's true anymore.
[woman 3] It's not the end
of the world, but you can see...
[man 3]
Power grid has collapsed.
[woman 4] Currency is worthless.
[man 4] Cities are burning.
[woman 5]
Pestilence and pandemics.
[man 5] Catastrophic heat.
[woman 6] We're actually
running out of water.
[man 6 shouting] Why are you
hurting these people?
[man 7] Getting close to
the terminal freak-out point.
[man 8] Mankind has gone rogue,
terrorizing itself.
Gangs are marauding
like locusts across the land.
[woman 7] The earth is sour.
[woman 8]
Our bones are poisoned.
[woman 9]
We have become half-life.
[History Man echoing]
As the world falls around us,
how must we brave its cruelties?
This one's for me.
[bees buzzing]
I'll get that one for you.
We should go back now.
We've come too far.
Furiosa!
[man] Hey, Vulture.
[Vulture] Shh! Not so loud.
[man] Have you ever seen
so much meat?
[whispering] Stay very still.
[man 2 laughing] Meat.
[bird squawking nearby]
Valkyrie, be invisible.
Still as a rock till I get back.
Be invisible.
[insects chirring]
[men muttering]
[Vulture] Careful.
Careful with the head.
[man] That spine's mine.
[Vulture] Cut right there.
[screams]
[blowing shrill whistle]
[metal scraping]
[whistle continues, faint]
[bearded man] Hear that?
[gulls squawking]
[grunts, gasping]
[men cackling]
[piercing whistle]
[alarms wailing]
[alarm continues in distance]
[motor starts]
Get on! Get on!
Furiosa! They took Furiosa!
[motors rumbling in distance]
[engines roaring nearby]
[motor starts]
[grunts]
[motor sputtering]
I'll come with you.
No, they need you here.
[speaking language
of the Green Place]
The stars be with you.
- [motor sputtering]
- [wheel squeaking]
[metal clanking]
[motor rumbling]
[breathing heavily]
[rifle cracks]
[Vulture] Snipers!
We got snipers.
[panting heavily]
[motor sputtering faintly]
Lone rider.
[spits]
[bike creaking, scraping]
[motor revving loudly]
[motor coughing, sputtering]
[motor dies]
She fouled us.
[growls]
She bit through it.
Hey! What are you doing?
Hey, give it. Give it. Give it!
[switches off motor]
[faint, rumbling motor]
That's the Thunderbike.
That's the Thunderbike!
[rumbling approaches]
- I thought you crippled it.
- I did!
Who's coming for us?
Who is... who is that?
Is that your pa?
- Is that your father? Who...
- [motor starts]
Hey. Hey, hey, hey. Hey!
Ditch the girl!
That's all he wants.
- What do we tell Dementus?
- [yells]
We got horse meat.
It proves nothing.
But the girl, once he sees her,
he's gonna ask,
"Where did she come from?"
And we're gonna be the ones
to tell him.
No one's gonna scum us anymore.
[both] No one's gonna
scum us anymore!
[laughing]
That piece of filth!
[yells]
[panting]
[grunting]
[yells]
[sand hissing on dune]
[exhales]
[wind blowing]
- Whoo-hoo!
- We're gonna make it.
- We're gonna make it!
- [cheering]
[tire shredding]
[bullet hisses]
I got news for Dementus.
Dementus!
What do you got here, Toe Jam?
All by yourself.
[Toe Jam]
I speak only to Dementus.
No. Hands off.
Untie it.
[Toe Jam]
I found it. She's mine.
Hands off.
It's strong. What a dilly, eh?
- [Toe Jam] She's mine.
- [man] Where did you find it?
- Give it back.
- Where?
- Where did you get it?
- Give her back.
Give her to me.
I'll take her to him.
She's from a place of abundance.
What are you talking about?
A place of abundance!
It's got everything!
Where?
I speak only to Dementus.
[growling] Where are you from?
[kindly voice]
Where are you from?
Where did you find her?
My lips, Dementus's ear.
My lips. Dementus.
[Toe Jam cackles]
[chokes, grunts]
Good girl.
[sand blowing]
[History Man] The original
JRL Cycles Lucky Seven
was powered by a seven cylinder
radial aircraft engine,
with a swept capacity
of 2,800cc's,
110 horsepower,
160 pounds of torque.
[man] Dementus.
- Dementus. Look what I found.
- [dogs barking]
Who do we have here?
[distant chatter outside]
What's your name?
What do they call you?
She's from a place of abundance.
- May I?
- [Dementus] Mm-hmm.
A healthy,
well-nourished full-life.
Flawless.
Tell us where
you're from, child. Eh?
Tell your friend.
It's got everything.
How do you know that?
A Roobilly told me.
He said he saw it
with his own eyes.
Hm.
And where is he?
Let's hear from Toe Jam.
Bring him in.
[dogs barking]
This place, where you found her,
it was amazing, right?
It had everything, right?
Water, food, everything.
[blood bubbling]
Tell me.
[breath shuddering]
[dogs barking frantically]
[man 2] He's choking.
Well, hang him upside down.
- [growls]
- [yelps]
[man] Downside up.
There you go.
[dogs barking, growling]
Draw a map.
Draw an arrow. Draw an arrow!
[men yelling]
Show us! Show us!
[sharp whistle]
[all fall silent]
[Dementus] Now, you have had
a hard day, haven't you?
An awful day.
You must be exhausted.
There's only one thing I need
you to do and that is rest.
You don't have to
tell us anything.
You don't have to say a word,
I promise.
Just rest.
Tomorrow, I'll take you home.
I'll follow the tracks
that brought you here
and I'll take you home.
Take her, feed her, wash her.
Use our best drinking water.
You two.
Keep an eye on her,
keep her safe.
Don't let any
of these brutes near her.
[dogs growling softly]
[dogs licking]
[motor rumbling]
[wind blowing]
[ball bearings clicking]
[tent rattling]
[man] Hey, what you got there?
[motorbike approaching]
[muted yell]
Snapper. Snapper!
[slingshot creaking]
Ma!
Please. I'm a mother, too.
[whimpering]
I will say nothing, not a word.
[motorbike revving]
[woman] Stop! Stop her!
- Shoot! Shoot! Shoot!
- Shoot!
[woman] It's not my fault.
[man] We've lost her!
[gasping]
[sizzling]
[mother] Good, we're good.
[shuts off motor]
[faint rumbling]
[Furiosa] You're bleeding.
Do you hear that? Come, quick.
[rumbling intensifies]
[motor starts]
[Furiosa]
How are they tracking us?
Ride to high ground.
Hide yourself well.
If I don't find you in one day,
go home.
Ma, I...
Take your bearings
from the sun and stars.
When there is wind,
use it to cover your tracks.
- I'm not gonna leave you.
- Furiosa!
You are Vuvalini,
you'll do as I ask.
[breath trembling]
Whatever you have to do,
however long it takes,
promise me
you'll find your way home.
Plant this seed.
Protect the Green Place.
Give me this one gift. Promise.
[motor rumbles to life]
[whispers]
The stars be with you.
[engines rumbling]
[gunshots echoing]
[gunshot]
[gunshots continue]
[Dementus] Go around!
Gotta go around!
Find a way around!
[bullet ricochets]
[grunts]
[men shouting]
[ravens cawing]
[mother screaming]
[Furiosa whimpering]
[screaming] Ma!
- [screams]
- [Furiosa] Ma!
[sobbing]
- Ahh...
- [interrogator] Tell me!
She's your mother. Perfect.
Where are you from?
Tell me!
[Furiosa] Ma!
Tell me where you came from
and we will cease and desist.
Furiosa! [screams]
- [sobbing]
- All you have to do...
All you have to do
is just point.
Point me in the right direction
and I'll take you home.
No, no, no. Don't look away.
We mustn't look away.
[interrogator]
You had your chance.
History Man,
a Word Burger, please?
Tears.
[History Man] Human tears.
The secretions of the lacrimal
gland containing oils,
salts, proteins,
and stress hormones.
The tears of joy
and those of sorrow
have different
chemical compositions.
Yes. Sorrow is more...
piquant, zesty.
[Furiosa crying]
[gunshot]
[Dementus] Why would you
run from me?
[groans]
Now your followers must fight
over who gets to kill you.
Now, I would've welcomed you.
Every one.
I woulda brought you in.
You coulda been a part
of this great horde.
Now, we have a problem.
There are 20 of you,
but only five bikes.
How do we choose?
Who's got the goods,
the bollocks, the testes
to ride with Dementus?
You're gonna have to show me
who you are.
Yes?
Because today
we dance to Darwin.
Today, we do
The Five Bike Teddy.
Ready, setty, go!
[all yelling, grunting]
[cackling]
[grunts]
You don't have to watch
if you don't want to.
You may wanna close your eyes.
You know,
you could hold this if you want.
It belonged to my little ones.
Why don't you
just keep him safe?
Lady and gentlemans,
start your engines.
[motors starting, revving]
[engines roaring]
Lizard mince
and human blood sausage.
[engines rumbling]
Can you write?
I can teach you.
Muscle up your memory.
You could become a History Man.
Make yourself invaluable,
and Dementus
will look after you.
[History Man] Astronavigation.
A determination of one's course
by reference to the stars
and other celestial bodies.
Red! Red!
Are we curious, boss?
Well, let's go have a look.
[War Boy] Is this Halvalla?
Am I in Valhalla?
What's Valhalla?
Valhalla's
"The Hall of the Slain."
A paradise for dead heroes.
Good for you.
We're looking for a place
of abundance.
What's abundance?
Abundance, plentifulness.
Having a copious quantity
of something.
[War Boy] Co...
What's "copus quantity"?
A lotta stuff.
A lotta good stuff.
[War Boy] The Citadel.
The what-a-del?
[War Boy]
It's where I was birthed.
It's got everything.
A humongous amount
of fresh water.
And green stuff.
Mountains of pro-juice
and veggies and... and water.
And where would one
find this Citadel?
That way maybe.
What are these?
That is sky blood.
It called you to me.
[flies buzzing]
[munching]
[swallows]
[overlapping chatter]
[motors thundering]
[motors revving thunderously]
[motors fall silent]
[History Man on loudspeaker]
Behold the might of Dementus!
The Red Dementus
and his Congress of Destruction.
He is here to lay siege on you.
Listen carefully to his words.
[voice echoing] All of you.
All who protect and honor
this magnificent Citadel,
you have a choice.
A very attractive choice.
I want your leaders.
[scattered cheering]
I want those
who hold dominance over you.
Bring me your leaders
and throw them down.
Throw them down,
and you'll avoid
more suffering and sorrow.
They exploit you.
They enslave you.
They wash their feet
in your sweat and blood
and they give you
nothing in return.
[cheering and laughter]
[Dementus] Listen to this truth.
Big shots rule only
because you choose to follow.
The power is with you.
You are free to choose.
Come to me.
Come to me
with your pain and burden,
and I will double your grub.
Food and water for everyone,
as much you like.
We will share the wealth.
You will rule with me in
the splendor of a new Wasteland.
[bikers cheering]
Adorable.
[laughter, jeers]
I'm afraid for you, sweetheart.
Really afraid.
'Cause Big Jilly here is gonna
scoop you out, both ends,
mush it up
and feed it back to you.
But that ain't nothing compared
to what Mr. Norton here
is dreaming of doing to you.
'Cause Mr. Norton
really hates big shots.
- Then there's Mr. Harley.
- G'day, mate!
Mr. Davidson, Rizzdale Pell
and a thousand other
mad bastards coming after you,
and there ain't nothing
I can do to stop 'em.
The Immortan has a request.
Among all his warriors
assembled here,
choose one.
Why would I do that?
For this negotiation
to go further,
you must choose at random.
Any War Boy. Just one.
What if I choose not to choose?
Then you'll never know
the truth.
My Smeg will choose.
Yes! [giggling]
Okay.
[Smeg] Nope. To the right.
[can clatters]
You are awaited.
Witness me!
[War Boys] Witness!
[War Boys] Immorta!
Among us
are 972 devout warriors.
Any one of them, if chosen,
would've done the same.
Each would die historic
for the Immortan Joe.
- That's why you're fools.
- [biker] You're the fool!
You're all fools
for coming here.
[Immortan Joe breathing deeply]
I am Scrotus.
I am Rictus.
We are the sons
of the Immortan Joe.
And now we're going to kill you.
[all yelling]
[biker yelling]
[grunting]
Hey!
[Furiosa straining]
- [flies buzzing]
- [grunting with effort]
I gotcha.
[explosions booming]
[Dementus] When things
go bonkers, you have to adapt.
- You, same as me.
- [puppy whines]
They're here.
We're tough.
- You're a tender little hound.
- [whimpering]
[Mr. Harley]
A War Rig. Fully loaded.
[The Octoboss] It's from
the Citadel, all right.
It's got the Immortan's mark.
Food and water for guzzolene.
It beats scavenging.
This is our destiny.
We are indeed
in the land of opportunity.
[engines rumbling faintly]
[men shouting in distance]
[faint gunfire]
Watch this.
[biker] All hail Dementus!
[bikers] Dementus!
Fuel for all, enough for months.
Thisis truly a great day.
Yeah, well, I'm about to make it
a whole lot greater.
Who are you?
Remove your helmet and jacket.
I take orders from The Octoboss.
[Dementus] Huh?
Yeah, do what he says.
[Dementus] Uh-uh...
Questioning my boss-ority.
[groans] Okay.
All right, that's good.
Right. Go on.
Cover yourself in this.
That's it.
Come on. Come on.
Good?
There ya go.
Choose ten of your men.
The balder the better.
Mortifiers.
[Dementus] Settle down.
Who wants to be a War Boy?
[line ringing]
[bell ringing weakly]
[ringing continues]
What?
[watchman] The rig's coming back.
I think they're under attack.
Do we open the gates?
No. Something's off.
I'm gonna have to slow down.
No. Faster. Go faster.
They won't open the gate.
They're not buying it.
Shoot them.
[biker] What?
Make it real.
[biker 2] What'd he say?
[biker 2] He wants us
to make it real.
[The Octoboss]
What are you doing?
[yells]
[rider] No, no. No, no, no!
You're scum, Dementus. Scum!
Open the gates.
Open the gates!
[horn blaring]
[gunshots]
Open the gates.
[bikers yelling]
[overlapping chatter]
[man] Back off.
[man 2] Get off.
[Smeg]
Give this to Immortan Joe.
Catch.
Dementus wants to talk.
[man] Are you sure?
[Immortan Joe]
Yes. Let him come.
Body search, no weapons.
Whatever he wants, we'll listen.
Then kill him on the spot.
[respirator hissing]
[Rizzdale] Calm down.
Calm down.
The Red Dementus commends you
on your lifestyle
and for agreeing to these
trade negotiations.
If we're not back safe
by sunset,
we blow up Gastown.
This is how you save Gastown.
[keys clicking]
[grunts softly]
And the six-figure code exists
only in the brain of Dementus.
He wants double.
Double of everything.
One full tank of water
for half a tank of guzzolene.
Can't do that. Not possible.
Then he gets a spike in the nut.
Double the mothers' milk
and double the hydroponics.
[man] Double the spuds.
Double the maggot mash
and the roach gruel.
My boys need all the protein
they can get.
[yelps]
Please. Give him what he wants!
The Wasteland won't sustain it.
Run the numbers.
Please, my Immortan. My brother.
[breath hissing]
[Dementus] Make up your mind.
Can't hold this much longer.
Let Rictus do it, Dad.
I'll squeeze
the code out of him.
- Here, take it. Take it.
- Huh?
- [pained grunt]
- [groans]
Oh, you idiot.
I've forgotten the numbers.
- [Dementus] Wait, wait, wait.
- [yells]
Wait! [groaning]
Yep, it's in there,
got it, got it, got it, okay.
[groans, shivers]
The pleasure flushed them
clean out of my head.
Don't ever do that again, comrades.
I'm a man with a fragile brain.
Who's that?
That... is my daughter,
Little D.
Little Dementus.
She looks nothing like you.
[Dementus] Yes, well, she has
her mother's perfections,
and none of my deficiencies.
[Immortan Joe]
Where's the mother?
[sighs] Magnificent woman.
Fierce, intelligent.
Taken so cruelly protecting
this little one from marauders.
She looks pale.
You look pale. She's perfect.
Not like the genetic absurdities
you have for sons.
[growls quietly]
Well, she's pale
because I take her blood,
for blood pudding
that I prepare for him.
And who are you?
Well, I'm the Organic Mechanic.
All things therapeutic.
Now, make no mistake,
she is a full-life.
Untouched by man or disease.
[breathes heavily]
Would you like to stay here
in the Citadel?
Eh?
[Immortan Joe]
If I let you stay and you grow
to become a strong,
healthy woman,
you could become
one of our wives.
No, she's my daughter.
It will be
a royal intermarriage.
The bonding of dynasties.
Her whole life
I have protected her,
from the sun, the wind,
every lecherous gaze.
No.
You'll be bonded by blood.
No! She's not for sale,
she's mine.
What say you, child?
She hasn't spoken
since her mother's tragic end.
Very poignant.
[breath hissing]
Is he your father?
No.
He slaughtered my mother.
True, that is true.
And I can tell you
it made this child tough.
Tough enough
to survive all sorrows
that may come her way.
I did that for her.
[softer] I did that for her.
I will increase
your shipment of water.
But only by a third.
I will increase your food
by a quarter.
Potatoes only.
You'll get your delivery
once every ten days,
but only if my War Rigs
return safely
full of high-grade guzzolene.
Deal.
And... I will take this girl,
who is not your daughter.
And also, him.
Otherwise, it's war.
[Dementus whistles sharply]
[grunts]
You behave, I'll behave.
I'll protect Gastown
from all treachery.
It will be as impenetrable
as this Citadel.
Stability born
from a world of chaos.
You. Me. We.
Henceforth, I will be addressed
as "The Great Dementus."
Beloved ruler of Bikerdom.
Lord Guardian of Gastown.
[cackling]
Gotta go, gotta go.
Don't want Gastown to go boom.
What a day.
What a deal. What a day.
[Rizzdale]
Beautifully played, boss.
- Peak Dementus! Eh? Eh?
- [men laughing]
[bells jingling]
It's all right.
You'll be all right.
[Organic Mechanic] All right.
Now, shove that little beauty
out into the world.
- [woman breathing heavily]
- [Organic Mechanic] Come on.
Here it comes.
I can see its head.
- [laughing]
- [heavy breathing continues]
[woman yelling hoarsely]
[Organic Mechanic]
Good girl. Good girl.
- [bells jingling]
- [Organic Mechanic] Oh, yeah.
You're very clever.
One last shove.
[woman gasping, yelling]
[Organic Mechanic]
One more, one more.
- [woman yelling, sobbing]
- Very good.
[newborn baby crying]
Is it a boy? Is it a boy?
[baby shrieks]
More or less.
Sorry, boss.
[woman]
I will give you a full-life!
I know that I can.
[Scrotus]
Three strikes, you're out.
- Rictus.
- [clap echoes]
[woman] Please, let me stay.
Don't fret, love.
You'll make an excellent milker.
[bells jingling softly]
[bells jingling]
[blade sawing at hair]
[Rictus] What's this?
[bells jingle]
[jingling]
[grunts]
[bells jingling]
Rictus. You lose something?
Just looking.
Just looking around.
What for?
Nothing.
No. Don't lie to me.
You're up to something.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Well, what're you
doing here then?
[bells jingling]
[Rictus] I thought
I saw someone running.
Running away.
But it was just a dream.
An annoying dream.
[footsteps receding]
[growls softly]
[feet thudding]
[breathing deeply]
- [wind blowing]
- [bells jingling faintly]
[bells jingling]
[man yells]
Brake!
Dogman. The loose cable!
Secure it!
[Scrotus] Save the bucket!
We need that bucket!
You go down.
No. Someone small.
You!
Come on.
No. Him.
[grunts softly]
[metal creaking]
You've got a lot of ticker, boy.
Brake Man.
You're the new dogman.
[Rictus] Line up. Line up.
Juva-jub-jub.
Welcome to the house
of holy motors.
We're gonna make us something
mighty from this boneyard,
from all these body parts.
Two hefty V8 engines,
a chassis for a Prime Mover,
2,857 found objects.
And we are going
to put this all together.
We are going to build
something beautiful.
And we're doing this for who?
- Immortan Joe.
- Who?
Who will raise us
from the ashes of this world.
Are you ready
to be Black Thumbs?
Immorta!
You?
How about you?
Speak his name.
He don't speak. He's mute.
Where have I seen you before?
He's a dogman. Very useful.
Scrawny.
Oi! We've got work to do.
We're going to build ourselves
a War Rig.
The finest piece of grunt
in the Wasteland.
Bigger, stronger, faster!
Immorta!
[all] Immorta! Immorta! Immorta!
[chanting continues]
[hydraulics whirring]
We are going to build
a contraption
that will defend the rear.
We will call it
"The Bommyknocker."
Is that the Praetorian Jack?
He looks lucky.
[War Boy] He done the most runs
on the Fury Road.
And brung back the booty
every time.
Hey. Prae Jack.
[ignition cranks]
[motor rumbles to life]
[no audible dialogue]
What's going on?
Why so shy? It's just piss.
They were right,
the crazy brothers.
She is a mighty thing.
Bigger, faster,
stronger, further.
[motor idling]
[man] Here it comes.
[motor fades into silence]
[motor rumbling]
They look like Mortifiers.
Mortifiers.
They ride with Dementus.
Not anymore. They've gone rogue.
Contact.
Contact front!
You, go!
[overlapping yells]
Contact right. Contact left.
[attackers yelling]
[War Boy] Crossbows, War Boys.
[War Boy 2] Load up.
[War Boy 3] Behind you!
Go!
[indistinct shouting]
- [horn honking]
- [man shouting outside]
[indistinct shouting]
[screaming]
Witness!
[grunting with effort]
[engine dying]
[Black Thumb] That's engine two.
All down on top. Replenish!
[horn bellowing]
[War Boys shouting]
[propeller motor fires up]
[indistinct shouting]
We need a short hose and clamps!
Short hose. Clamps.
[screams]
[grunts]
[yells warning]
[gasps]
[aggressive grunting]
Yes!
Black Thumb? Black Thumb.
[horn blasts]
Up front.
Can I do the Bommyknocker?
- What?
- The Bommyknocker.
Not yet.
[War Boy] Eyes left.
They're flanking us.
Eyes right. Eyes right.
They're swarming.
Black Thumb.
[Praetorian Jack]
Black Thumb! Are you there?
[motor roaring]
Now hang tight.
[tires scraping]
[laughs triumphantly]
Prae Jack! Prae Jack!
Pissboy. Pissboy!
We got a busted radiator.
[Pissboy]
Copy P-Jack. On my way.
Drink, my rig. Drink this piss.
[War Boy] Come on.
[all grunting]
[grunts]
Prae Jack.
- [bottle whirring]
- [gun blasts]
Witness!
[gun clicks]
[grunts]
[coughing]
[yells]
- [yells]
- No!
[fierce grunt]
[automatic gunfire]
[machine gun fire]
[grunts, panting]
[The Octoboss screams, growls]
[motor whining]
The Bommyknocker!
Do the Bommyknocker!
- Now?
- Now!
[gunfire continues]
[gun clicking]
[lever thuds]
[Bommyknocker powers down]
[grunts]
Pull over.
You're going to pull over
and get out.
Stop!
[yelps]
[grunts]
[panting hoarsely]
[screams]
[panting]
[Praetorian Jack] Where did
you think you were going?
If you're running away
from the Citadel,
believe me, the Bullet Farm
is a whole lot worse.
The only other place is Gastown.
It's in the hands of Dementus.
A mug who can't even
keep his gangs together.
And that's it.
There is nowhere else.
This is the Wasteland.
Wherever you thought
you were going does not exist.
It's been a hard day.
I lost my convoy.
I lost my crew.
I'm gonna have to start again.
And I'm driving off thinking
I ought to start with you.
You got good vision.
You read the play
and you keep your head.
You may be raw,
but you have about you
a purposeful savagery.
You give me time,
I'll teach you everything
you need to know about Road War.
If you survive everything
we take on together,
you'll have
all the skills you need
to get wherever you wanna go.
No questions asked.
Keep it. You'll need it.
[mother] The stars be with you.
The stars be with you.
[Dementus] You and me, Little D.
[gunshot echoing]
[men chanting and
clapping rhythmically]
[all cheering]
[all chanting] Immortan Joe!
[continuing, indistinct]
[chanting fades]
[indistinct chatter, shouting]
[War Boy] Two... four...
six... eight...
Done. Tank's empty.
Everything accounted, down to
the last drop of Mother's Milk.
- Good.
- No, it's not good.
That piece of anus-pus,
Dementus,
is running Gastown
into the ground
and blaming everyone
but himself.
You tell Immortan Joe
we need a meeting.
A war meeting.
Otherwise we're gonna get
our tits caught in the wringer.
Here's the boomstick
you asked for.
[Furiosa] Thundersticks.
Bullets all loaded.
[engine cranks, starts]
[War Boy shouting indistinctly]
For you.
For your travels.
You're done here.
You're free to go.
Food, water, wheels,
whatever you need.
I'll help you put it together.
Give me a couple of days.
[gasps]
[panting]
[warning horn blaring]
[machinery clanking]
[gate rumbling]
[coughs]
We'll lead you in.
[gate hinges creaking]
[crowds shouting, yelling]
[indistinct shouting]
Move! Hurry up! Come on!
Back! Get out then!
[gunshots]
[Dementus, over P.A.] Stay back!
Back! Stand back.
Citizens of Gastown.
I want what you want.
A full belly...
and a fistful of bullets
for a tank of gas.
We have to put things right.
And today, we're gonna
do something about it.
Are you in charge here?
You can speak to me.
[Dementus] Yeah.
Well, I've got a message
for Immortan Joe.
We're in a black spiral here.
We can't keep up supply.
Everyone is saying they're being
swindled and short-changed.
Everyone is saying
it's my fault.
It's everyone's fault.
I want a meeting
of the warlords.
Me, him, the People Eater,
that idiot Bullet Farmer.
High noon at the Citadel.
Three days from now.
Right.
[crowd yelling angrily]
- Ah, you better go.
- [dogs snarling]
We're not leaving
without our tankers full of gas.
[muffled boom]
Go now.
[explosions booming]
[all shouting, indistinct]
You wanna get out of here,
follow me.
[engine roaring]
[yelling]
[crowd roaring angrily]
High noon, the Citadel,
three days from now.
Be punctual.
[flies swarming]
[sighs deeply]
[People Eater] You give him
a full tank of water,
and 2,000 tits of Mother's Milk
and then you return
empty-handed.
Not a drop of guzzolene.
He filched us.
We're being filched.
Let's kill him. Right now.
Shoulda done it long ago, Dad.
Shoulda crushed him, Dad!
Father, give me the War Rig.
Load it up with all
of the firepower you've got,
and I will blow him
from the face of the earth.
[People Eater] How do we do that
before he blows up Gastown?
We'll build it again.
That'd take generations,
you moron.
We will build it again.
Your way of thinking
is how he rooks us.
He's got you scared
of his crazy.
Bah!
[Immortan Joe]
Here's what we do!
We conserve every drop
of guzzolene,
turn off all vehicles,
all generators.
Turn off every water pump
including the Big Four
Aquifer Siphons.
Get.
At first light, leave
for Bullet Farm
with your tankers empty.
Then, return with every munition
you can load.
I want every bullet and firearm,
every caliber and size.
Your entire infantry
ready to pick up.
Good.
Come to the watchtower.
We'll signal them now.
[Scrotus] Hell and Hall-elujah!
We're gonna take Gastown.
[Rictus] Hit him! Hit him
when he least suspects it.
[People Eater] How do we
stop him blowing up Gastown?
[tools scraping]
This place at the end
of your map of secrets.
Where is it?
My mother and father...
were soldiers.
Even as the world fell,
they yearned to be warriors
for a virtuous cause.
For them, it never happened.
I wanna help you
find this place.
Wherever it may be.
Come with me.
[Furiosa] Ready?
[horn blaring]
[hydraulics hissing]
[Praetorian Jack]
I want your bikes.
Load them on the back
of the V8 Pursuit
and tie them down.
- [War Boys shouting]
- Soon as that's done,
load it with food,
fuel and water.
As much as you can carry.
[War Boy] What's this?
A scouting party?
[Praetorian Jack] Possibly.
[War Boy 2] What about us?
[Praetorian Jack] You're both
gonna ride on the tanker.
What about me?
You're promoted. Rear defense.
- On the War Rig?
- Of course.
What are you doing?
Is there a problem?
You drive the V8.
I drive the War Rig.
Not today.
Today you drive Pursuit.
[driver] What am I gonna do?
[Praetorian Jack]
You're with me.
- Up front?
- Up front.
As soon as we load up
the weapons and munitions,
you can drive the rig back.
[driver] All the way home?
To the Citadel?
- [Praetorian Jack] Yep.
- [driver laughs]
[Praetorian Jack] Go on.
[driver] Whoo!
[truck engine starts]
[horn honking]
Wanna see what this can do?
Hit the second engine.
[engine ignites, starts]
[driver whooping joyfully]
[truck horn blaring]
[truck hisses, falls silent]
[horn blaring]
[gunfire]
[biker] All dead?
[biker 2] Don't know.
- [gunshot]
- [biker 3] Sniper ambush!
[biker]
He's got backup. Outside.
[biker 4] Between the tanks.
[bullet clangs]
[biker] I can't see him.
[panting]
[gunshot]
[biker 5] Behind you.
[body thuds]
[motorcycle approaching]
[gunshot]
[gasps]
[motor revving]
[panting deeply]
[honking horn]
[vehicles approaching]
[flare gun clicks]
[boom echoing]
[engines roaring]
[grunts]
[shifts gears]
[panting deeply]
[Dementus, faintly] Do not miss.
[breathing hoarsely]
- [bullet whistles]
- Whoo!
[bullet hisses]
Where are they?
Can you see them?
[bullet hisses]
On the ridge,
to the left of the gate.
[people screaming]
Give me that.
All right, load me up.
Come on.
Come here.
[exclaiming]
[rumbling]
[powerful thud]
[people screaming]
Jack!
Yeah? We're good.
We'll head east for three days.
Once we clear the escarpment
and the great salt plains,
we'll take the bikes
over the dunes all the way.
All the way.
The digger.
Let's use the digger.
No time.
Out.
[growling]
[engine roaring]
Fang it! Fang it!
[screams]
[sound fades]
[engine shuts off]
[grunting with effort]
Hello?
Heh?
[motorbikes approaching]
[grunting]
[bikers cheering]
[man] This one's still alive!
[Dementus] Good.
[Furiosa gasping]
[man 2] Get up here.
Come on, get up here.
Did you see that?
You see how they fought
for each other,
this little army of two?
Where were they going,
so full of hope?
There is no hope!
Not for them, not for you!
Certainly not for me!
[biker whimpers, yelps]
The day I acquire Bullet Farm,
these two destroy it.
I had Gastown,
I had Bullet Farm.
With that,
I coulda crippled the Citadel.
- Jack.
- Ruled the Wasteland!
- The Wasteland woulda been...
- My Jack.
A far better place
for all of us.
[Praetorian Jack] Fury.
- Jack.
- No!
[man 2] Get up.
[voice strained] You two.
You two break my heart.
You break my heart.
And that's not fair.
You make me the Dark Dementus.
The Dark Dementus
cannot afford to be soft!
It's the price I pay
to be your leader!
It's the price we all pay
to survive in the Wasteland.
We cannot be soft!
There must be retribution.
Justice and retribution.
[motors starting]
[cackling]
[Dementus] Hey, hey, hey!
I want her to watch a while.
String her up.
You're going. You're going.
You're going.
[man] Let's go.
No, mate, other arm.
What? You lost your touch?
[growls]
[Mr. Norton] I'll do it.
- [winch whirring]
- [gasps]
[biker] Come on, piggy!
Get up. Get up!
Let's go. Go.
[growling, barking]
Smeg!
[amplified] Enough! Enough!
[quietly] I'm bored.
Let's end our cares and go home!
[shouting, indistinct]
[engine roaring]
[metal breaking]
[motor revving]
[panting heavily]
[ravens crying in distance]
[flies buzzing]
[gasping violently]
[old woman] It's all right.
Go back to sleep.
I'll make it nice for you.
Stay!
You'll find peace here.
[people shouting]
[yelling]
I'm the Praetorian Furiosa.
[angry yell]
I am the Praetorian Furiosa!
What happened to you?
Pull.
[Bullet Farmer] Any sign of him?
[Rictus] No.
But there's something going on
at Gastown.
I think he's blowing up Gastown.
[Bullet Farmer] Rubbish.
- Take a look.
- [growls]
[People Eater] He fails to turn
up to a meeting and now this.
[Immortan Joe] It's fake.
There's no possible advantage.
We shouldn't have waited.
Why're we waiting now?
Let's go to Gastown now.
[Furiosa] He's not at Gastown.
[Bullet Farmer]
Where's Praetorian Jack?
Where's our War Rig?
[Furiosa]
He's taken the Bullet Farm.
You're lying.
[Furiosa] He's taken
the Bullet Farm,
and he's coming here next.
How do you know that?
They're coming with
grappling hooks and ladders.
He wants to take the Citadel.
[Bullet Farmer]
Then we go to the Bullet Farm.
Meet him head-on right now.
It's Gastown that's burning.
He's at Gastown.
He wants to draw you to Gastown.
He wants you to leave
the Citadel exposed.
So we stay here.
We have three choices.
The coward's choice.
Stay here and let Dementus
mess with our minds.
The fool's choice,
go out and meet
an invisible enemy
on the road to the Bullet Farm.
Or the warrior's choice,
go to Gastown and crush him.
[Immortan Joe] It is my choice.
We make him think
we're going to Gastown.
[growls]
If you find him, he's mine.
Yes. Yes!
[Smeg] They're Gastown bound
for sure.
[Dementus] So gullible.
I hold them profoundly
in contempt.
Gentlemans, it's time.
Time to do war.
Time to take back
what's rightfully ours.
To the Citadel.
Let's party!
[bikers roaring]
[gears whirring]
[History Man]
There always was, is,
and will be war.
The Sumerian fought the Elamite.
The Saxon fought the Viking.
And so the histories grew.
There were the Wars
of the Roses,
The Oranges.
The Opium Wars.
The One-Day, Six-Day,
Thousand-Day Wars.
North against South.
East against West.
The first, second,
third countless wars
of religion
and righteous belief.
The Oil Wars. Water Wars.
The Tri-Nation Nuclear War.
The Battle of the Boomtowns.
And now, my dears...
The Forty-Day Wasteland War.
Eyes for eyes.
Teeth for teeth.
Rage fueled by grief.
[Furiosa] I need a vehicle.
There's nothing here,
not even a bike.
- [Furiosa] Winch me down.
- What're you gonna do? Walk?
I've got a vehicle.
Can't wait for you to see it.
Isn't she wonderful?
[chuckles]
[stops engine]
[War Boy] Hey! Look at this.
I think this one might fit.
[Scrotus] Try it on! Try it on!
Every moment wasted,
that mongrel gets
farther and farther away.
[War Boy] Coming up!
[Scrotus]
And I want her fuel too.
I want all of her fuel,
and her water and her weapon.
A fool can run,
but he can't hide.
It's gonna fit.
[Organic Mechanic] Hey, Scrotus.
- Scrotus!
- What?
You'll need some proper tucker.
- Canine kebab.
- [dismissive growl]
[Rictus] We'll take it with us.
What do you mean, "us?"
I'm coming with you.
[Scrotus] No, you're not.
You'll slow me down.
[Rictus] I'm gonna make sure
that dumb Dementus is dead.
[Scrotus] No, you're not!
You stay here and eat some dog.
[engine roaring]
[Scrotus] What was that?
[History Man]
That is the darkest of angels.
The fifth Rider
of the Apocalypse.
[bullet whistles, thuds]
[bullet strikes]
[panting]
Who are they?
Someone competent
and excessively resentful.
Who do you suppose they want?
Me, without my crew.
We'll wait here. Ambush him.
[Big Jilly] Let's go back.
[Dementus] No, no, no.
We have to split up.
Here, no time for long goodbyes.
We've done some
mighty things together.
Goodbye.
[squawking]
[engine revs]
I'm not Dementus!
We swapped bikes!
[panicked shout]
[faint cheering]
[wind whistling]
[takes deep breath]
[panting]
You've found me.
Freakish.
You are a freak.
You could have necked me
in the night, but you didn't.
So, you must be
that other thing.
Are you that thing?
[exhales sharply]
[panting]
[panting heavily]
[gun clatters]
[motor switches off]
[Dementus] I have nothing.
I am nothing.
[door closes]
I'm yours.
[chains jingling]
[Furiosa] Remember me?
You fabulous thing.
You crawled
out of a pitiless grave,
deeper than Hell.
And only one thing's
gonna do that for you.
And not hope. Hate.
No shame in hate.
It's one of the great forces
of nature.
That wasn't hope,
that was instinct.
[water drop splashes]
[splash]
So...
this is the day I die.
I've always wondered how...
[chokes]
Fifteen years ago
there was a woman.
Oh, so there's more to this.
Do you remember her?
Do I get a clue?
Right, okay. Um...
Redhead. Even her pu...
[grunts]
Was she your mother? Sister?
Did she beg, did she scream?
The ones who yell the least tend
to stick in my mind. [groaning]
[coughs]
Despite everything
you did to her,
she was magnificent.
Oh, you were there.
[groans]
My childhood. My mother.
I want them back.
Of course you do.
I want them back!
That's exactly how I felt.
My own family.
My own magnificent beauties.
Taken so unjustly. Immutably.
I'm right there,
I'm right there with you.
I too craved nothing
but revenge.
A big bellyful of revenge.
[gun clicks]
[growls] If I may...
If the shooter goes
around the back,
the shootee won't know
the precise moment
of the execution.
Minor torture,
but every little bit counts.
Either way, that rat shot
will turn my brain
into a pink mist so fast,
I won't even hear
the sound of the gun.
I'll hear it.
I'll hear it for the rest
of my days.
[Dementus] Of course you will.
I'll feel the kickback
in my hand.
[Dementus] Sure.
I'll remember your face.
As the slug worms its way
into the soft matter
of your brain,
taking with it what you call
your reason.
And your memory,
from which my mother
will fortunately be absent.
Brilliant.
I'll be dead and you'll
still be sorrowing
your lovey-dovey and
your mommy magnificent.
You idiot.
You can never balance
the scales of their suffering.
[groans softly]
- Give them back.
- I can't!
What you want, dear,
are my cries of anguish.
Anguish without end.
And if I could give you that,
I would.
But I don't fear
the loss of bliss in Heaven.
Or retribution in Hell.
And I've got a fiendishly high
pain threshold.
- [Furiosa shrieks]
- Again, do it again.
[yells, panting]
[panting] If you
can't do me quick,
you'll have to do me slow.
[spits]
But you are never going to get
anything close to what you want.
[grunting]
[gun hits the sand]
[tiny motor running]
Little D?
[laughing weakly]
I have been waiting for you.
I've been waiting
for someone like you,
someone worthy of me.
No honor, no rule of law
to sort things out.
Just two evil bastards
out here in the Wasteland.
You do this, you do this right,
you become me.
- I am nothing like you.
- You are me.
Already dead.
To feel alive,
we seek sensation.
Any sensation to wash away
the cranky black sorrow.
And it leaves us for a moment,
but then it comes back,
and we have to do it all again.
And we need more,
and each time we need more
until too much is never enough.
We are the already dead,
Little D.
[panting]
You and me.
[rumbling groan]
[wheezing]
The question is...
do you have it in you
to make it epic?
[History Man]
She took away his voice,
and they spent the rest
of the day in silence.
There are those who prefer
that she did
more than shoot him.
They claim that she ended him
in ways more fitting.
They tell
of righteous perversities
and witty mutilations.
But this is the truth whispered
to me by Furiosa herself.
Deep in the Citadel,
high up
in the hydroponic gardens,
there is a tree
unlike any other.
[wheezing breaths]
Its soil is human.
Its nutrients human.
Maggots debriding
his necrotic flesh.
It was an echo
growing out of a living being.
[Furiosa]
This is our first fruit,
but it's not for you and me.
Each of us in our own way
will vanish from this Earth.
And then perhaps...
some uncorrupted life
will rise to adorn it.
[thud, echoing]