WOMAN: (OVER PA SYSTEM)
Flight 291 is now boarding.
All passengers
please proceed to Gate 1.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(SIGHS)
CUSTOMS AGENT:
Please state your name.
Rebecca Smallbone, sir.
- Your name?
- Daniel Smallbone.
Ben. (HESITATES) Benjamin.
Uh, Joel.
Luke.
Joshua.
So just the six kids then, huh?
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
So tell me, uh,
what are you doing in America?
Ma'am, I'm gonna have to ask you
to look forward, please.
Tell me, what's your name?
Ma'am, your name.
(PA SYSTEM DINGS)
G'day and good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome aboard
Qantas Flight 199,
with service from Sydney
to Los Angeles.
Flight time will be 14 hours
and 32 minutes.
We ask that you remain seated
until the captain turns off
the seatbelt sign,
at which time it will
be safe to...
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
DAVID: Everybody
get ready to rock
'cause all the way
from the U.S.A...
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome, Stryper!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
So good, Joshie.
STRYPER MEMBER:
To hell with the devil!
♪ To hell with the devil ♪
♪ Well, speak of the devil ♪
- Art!
- David.
- Hey. (CHUCKLES)
- You did it again.
I told 'em back home,
"You wanna conquer
the outback, I got your guy."
- Oh, look.
- Amazing.
Every promoter dreams
of bands like this.
So, it makes my job easy.
Hey,
have you met my better half?
Hi. Helen.
Wow. Helen.
- HELEN: Oh.
- (KISSES)
Your much better half.
David, listen.
I've been talking with
Eddie DeGarmo and Dana Key,
- planning an Australian tour.
- Oh, yeah. Okay.
With all due respect,
that's a bit of a step back.
Right?
I mean, hey,
look at the audience.
The Australian crowd,
they've delivered,
I've delivered.
We're ready for more.
We're ready for Amy.
Now, look, man,
that's way more
than a step forward.
- Ah.
- Getting her band,
bringing production down here.
Yeah, we'd make back every cent.
Look,
she's at the top of her game.
I'm at the top of mine.
One plus one equals three.
All right, look.
I'll talk to her team.
We'll catch up.
DAVID: All right.
ART: Just give a listen.
- Think about it.
- DAVID: Thanks very much.
Might be... (KISSES)
another late one.
Kiss the kids goodnight for me.
Good night.
STRYPER MEMBER:
♪ With the devil ♪
(PA SYSTEM DINGS)
(SEATBELT CLICKS)
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
You okay?
You should go to sleep now, okay?
LUKE: Can Dad come tuck me in?
Oh, he's at work, honey.
Why is he working all the time?
Well, takes a lot
to live out your dream.
You know, a lot of hard work
and sacrifice.
(KISSES)
Do you have a dream, Mum?
My dream has always been
to have a great, big family.
So you've already got
your dream, then.
Night, Lukey.
So, this is it, huh?
It's a done deal?
I've gotta crosscheck
a couple of deal points,
but it's as good as done, yeah.
Well, I am proud of you,
however it goes.
Oh, there's only one way
it can go, darling.
It's Amy Grant.
I always loved your optimism.
It's just a lot of money.
And I feel like we're putting
our lives on the line.
You don't think I'm up for it?
No. I... You know I do.
I'm just not sure I am.
It's not just the finances.
The kids miss you. I miss you.
I know.
Look, it's a two-week tour.
I'll take one of the boys.
And then they'll all
settle down.
We'll go on holidays.
What do you reckon?
Nothing in this business
is ever 100%.
But this is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity, darl.
She'll be all right.
PAUL KEATING: (ON TV)
And the first thing to say is
that the accounts do show
that Australia's in a recession.
This is a recession
that Australia had to have.
NEWS ANCHOR: And that was
our Deputy Prime Minister,
Paul Keating.
In other news, American artist,
Amy Grant finishes off
her coast-to-coast tour tonight
at the Opera House.
And now here's
her number one hit,
- Lead Me On.
- (CROWD CLAPPING)
You're listening to Triple FM.
They're thrilled
to have you here.
It's gonna be a great show,
David.
I'm so sorry, Amy.
Hey.
(CROWD CHEERING)
♪ Lead me on, lead me on ♪
♪ To a place
where the river runs ♪
♪ Into Your keeping, oh ♪
♪ Lead me on, lead me on ♪
♪ The awaited deliverance... ♪
(AIRPLANE RUMBLING)
(PA SYSTEM DINGS)
FLIGHT ATTENDANT: (OVER PA)
Ladies and gentlemen,
looks like we're headed through
a little bit of a rough patch.
So let's buckle those seatbelts.
If you look out the left side
of the aircraft,
you'll see a glorious sunrise.
We're four hours
from the United States.
(BABY COOING)
DAVID: I had the billboards,
the radio ads,
TV spots, flyers...
ART: And I had
two other promoters
begging for your job,
but I gave it to you.
DAVID: And then
the economy crashed...
Look, it doesn't matter.
It's your job
to put butts in seats.
- There's more to...
- It's your job to do the math
like you said you could.
I did everything I know to do.
And look,
tell Amy that again, I'm...
Amy doesn't know about this
and she doesn't need to.
Because she'd give you
the shirt off her back,
if I'd let her.
But I can't.
I have to look out for her.
I got a crew to pay
and promises to keep.
Art. I'm gonna lose everything.
Man, I wish I could help you.
You signed the contract,
brother.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(SLOW TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC SWELLS)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
Kids?
- Helen?
- HELEN: We're in the backyard!
- PARTY GUESTS: Surprise!
- (PARTY HORN HONKING)
MAN: Hip-hip!
PARTY GUESTS: Hurray!
PARTY GUESTS: ♪ For he's
a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ For he's a jolly
good fellow ♪
♪ And so say all of us... ♪
- (PARTY HORN HONKING)
- (PARTY GUESTS CHEERING)
(HELEN LAUGHING)
Happy birthday, darling.
- How ya going, old bloke?
- Dad.
(CHUCKLES) Hi. Hey.
Happy birthday, my boy.
Oh, I think we got him, hey,
Grandpa James?
- I think so.
- Are you surprised, Dad?
- Are you?
- I couldn't be more surprised.
(HELEN LAUGHING)
JOSHUA: Let's party!
LUKE: Yeah!
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
MAN: That rhythmical beat,
so strong
in the Australian nation.
You wanna clap your hands
or anything,
don't feel shy or embarrassed.
DANIEL: All the Roosters
have signed it.
- Oh, wow. Blow me down.
- (PARTY GUESTS LAUGHING)
Right, thank you, boys.
Thanks, darling.
- (GLASS CLINKING)
- JAMES: I...
I will begin by thanking
Hel herself...
(PARTY GUESTS LAUGHING)
I meant to say Helen,
for this very grand party,
and for the way
she's loved my son.
And for giving me,
not one, not three,
but six grandchildren.
(PARTY GUESTS LAUGHING)
You're the family glue, Hel.
And now on
to the man of the hour.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
My old man of a son,
David Tom.
You've always been a renegade,
David.
Dreamed big, sometimes too big
for my comfort,
and, uh, for Helen's too,
I'm sure.
(HELEN CHUCKLES)
But you've always
found your footing.
You've provided.
You've achieved so much.
But look around you, David.
Your wife, your family...
Your faith.
Now, son, that's what
makes you rich in life.
Yours is the earth
and everything that's in it.
To David.
ALL: To David.
CHILDREN: To Dad.
Okay, okay. One more prezzie.
Thank you, darl.
HELEN: Surprise, my love.
(MAN GASPS)
Aw.
- (ALL CHEERING, LAUGHING)
- (SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
PARTY GUESTS:
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- ♪ Happy birthday, dear David ♪
- ♪ Happy birthday, dear Dad ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
(PARTY GUESTS CHEERING,
APPLAUDING)
HELEN: What is it
you're not telling me?
I'm worried about you
and what the doctor said
when you had Josh.
Oh, darl, I'm not.
Don't worry.
That's not it, is it?
What's wrong?
It's all right.
I'll sort it out.
Okay.
What is it you're sorting out?
- Helen, I...
- (SIGHS) David.
(DAVID SIGHS)
It's the Amy tour.
I'm gonna lose
half a million dollars.
Helen. I'm sorry.
No one anticipated this economy.
(SLOW SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING)
We're gonna lose everything.
(RETCHING)
(CONTINUES RETCHING)
(TOILET FLUSHING)
(SIGHS)
(LINE RINGING)
EDDIE: Hello?
DAVID: Eddie DeGarmo.
Uh, David Smallbone
in Australia.
EDDIE: The David Smallbone
from Australia
is the only David Smallbone
I know.
Right.
Hey, you still looking to come
down here, uh, to tour?
We're not hoping, we're coming.
- You still need a promoter?
- We got it figured out.
Found someone
who actually believes in us.
I believe in you.
Couple months ago,
shoe was on the other foot,
wasn't it?
I gotta get back to bed.
By the way, do you know
what time it is over here?
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
DAVID: Robert, g'day.
David Smallbone here.
How are ya?
Yeah, just checking in to see
if you need a hand...
Dave. How are you, young Sheila?
Right. Right, give me a ring.
Need any assistance?
Look, I'm free to do
whatever you'd like.
Rosie. David, here.
Yeah, it's been donkey's ages.
Hey, Chris, how ya going?
Liam, howdy.
You know any openings?
I'll, uh, I'll be glad
to help out...
Well, I'm around.
Yeah, we're doing all right.
Thanks for asking.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
CARMAN: (OVER PHONE) David.
How's life down under?
Oh, I was, uh,
hoping you'd come find out.
You know, I'd love to.
We're running fast
and pushing hard over here.
Oh, that's commendable.
Unless you're running
in circles, obviously.
Are you?
Darling, it's Carman.
He's a major artist.
- (PANTING)
- And, it's Nashville.
It's where the industry is.
- It's where one industry is.
- It's the only one I know.
Yeah, and we have to move
halfway around the world for it.
You married me for adventure.
Yeah, when I was 20.
Is there really no other way?
I could go ahead
for a few months
and get everything set...
No, we don't
break up the family.
We stay together.
(HELEN SIGHS)
Darling, I'm done in.
There's nothing
left for us here.
Oh, Bec just got lead vocals
in school band.
Daniel's made the swim team.
Joshie's about to go
into year one.
What, we just pluck 'em
out of school?
We couldn't afford to keep 'em
in school,
even if we stayed.
Yeah, but I'm saying
they have lives.
We have lives.
And friends and family.
And also, I'm preggers.
So how can we say goodbye
to everything
that we know and love
without being sure
that there's absolutely
no other way?
Helen, you know
I'd do any job for you.
- But the economy's wrecked.
- (SIGHS)
I'm 40.
Music is all I know.
It's what I was made to do.
I can't sing, I can't play,
but I can connect an artist
to an audience.
I can connect people
to something
higher and greater
than the here and now.
I don't want the kids
to see me settle,
'cause I don't want them
to settle.
I wanna do something
that matters.
- And this is it.
- (SIGHS)
This is my last chance.
(SIGHS)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Two years. We can do two years.
That's enough time for you
to have a real go.
And it also gives us an out
if things aren't working.
Two years.
(KISSES)
Just read it when you get there.
(SOBBING) Love you.
Keep telling myself,
it's just two years.
Your visa says six months.
Yeah, well, we'll have to renew.
Oh, surely by then,
you'll all have come
to your senses, love.
(SIGHS)
Applied for all the kids,
did you?
Mum.
Can't wait to see you again.
(SOBBING)
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
Sad to see you go,
but it'll be good for you.
All of you.
Great things in store.
Don't let him miss it,
all right?
(JAMES SNIFFLES)
"If you can dream..."
"And not make dreams
your master..."
"You'll be a man, my son."
(KISSES)
- I'll keep him in check.
- I know you will.
Go give America
all the hell they can handle.
Okay.
(AIRPLANE THUDDING)
(PA SYSTEM DINGS)
FLIGHT ATTENDANT: (OVER PA)
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's our pleasure to welcome you
to Los Angeles, California,
also known
as The City of Angels.
For your safety and the safety
of those around you,
please remain seated
with your seatbelt fastened,
and keep the aisles clear
until we're parked at the gate.
(UPBEAT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, stay close. Let's go.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
How many?
Uh, eight of us.
Two adults and six kids.
Catholic?
What brings you and six kids
to the United States,
Mr. Smallbone?
Well, if I was gonna come up
with a fake name,
it wouldn't be that one, right?
Yeah.
Uh...
In the music industry.
Here to start a record label
with an artist.
How long you intend to stay?
- Six months and...
- Two years.
You told us two years.
These here are six-month visas.
Right. If needed, we'd apply
for an extension, of course.
I'm gonna have to ask you
to step aside.
I'll be right with you.
Door to the side, please.
Let's go, kids.
Let's go this way.
(LUGGAGE UNZIPS)
CUSTOMS AGENT: So tell me, uh,
what are you doing in America?
Ma'am, I'm gonna have
to ask you to look forward.
We're gonna miss our flight.
If they don't send us back home.
CUSTOMS AGENT: What's your name?
Ma'am, your name.
Oh, sorry. Helen Smallbone.
Oh. That's from my mum.
Ma'am, you're gonna
need to stand back.
- I'm not gonna ask you again.
- (SNIFFLES, SOBS)
(JOSHUA SOBBING)
Joshie. (SHUSHES)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(JOSHUA CONTINUES SOBBING)
(SOFTLY) The baby's onesie.
- (SNIFFLES)
- HELEN: Joshie, no.
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
Stop crying, all right?
Please stop crying.
CUSTOMS AGENT: Ma'am,
keep him quiet
or we'll need to separate you.
(JOSHUA CONTINUES SOBBING)
Shut those tears off right away.
Okay? Shut 'em off.
You be a big boy now.
REBECCA: Josh. Stop it!
(JOSHUA CONTINUES SOBBING)
♪ For the rhythm of my heart ♪
♪ It's beating like a drum ♪
♪ With the words "I love you"
Rolling off my tongue ♪
(JOSHUA STOPS SOBBING)
REBECCA:
♪ No, never will I roam ♪
♪ For I know my place is ♪
♪ Home ♪
♪ Where the ocean
meets the sky ♪
♪ I'll be sailing ♪
CUSTOMS AGENT:
You're free to go.
(HELEN SIGHS)
CUSTOMS AGENT:
You can thank your mom.
Fine, let's go.
Kids, get your things.
HELEN: We gotta go.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
Welcome to America.
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
Hey, I think this is us, guys.
Hi, there.
How're you all doing today?
DAVID: Oh,
we're in a terrible state.
We got stuck in Customs,
and coppers kept us
in secondary for donkey's ages,
the kids are knackered.
Can we still get to Nashville
this arvo?
I, I'm sorry. What?
Uh, what he meant to say
is that we're all pretty weary
and we got pulled aside
by Customs agents
and I think we've missed
our flight to Nashville.
Could you maybe check
if there's another flight
this afternoon?
TICKET AGENT: Of course, ma'am.
- Why didn't he just say so?
- (KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Uh, nothing with eight seats
for another three days.
- Oh, fair dinkum!
- TICKET AGENT: Sonny,
I'm gonna have to ask you
to watch your language.
HELEN: We so appreciate
you checking.
Do you have any other ideas?
(RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW
BY JESUS JONES PLAYING)
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION)
♪ A woman on the radio
Talks about revolution ♪
♪ When it's already
passed her by ♪
♪ Bob Dylan didn't have this
to sing about ♪
♪ You know it feels good
to be alive ♪
♪ I was alive
and I waited, waited ♪
♪ I was alive ♪
WOMAN: (OVER PA SYSTEM)
Attention, please.
The train is approaching
Kansas City Union Station.
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
CARMAN: This is Carman.
Leave a message
- after the beep.
- (BEEP)
Hey, sorry to keep missing you.
We've had a few delays.
Just a couple days out.
I'm really looking forward
to getting started.
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
CONTINUES)
DAVID: Yeah,
this is us on the right.
Thanks very much for the ride.
- How much do we owe you?
- TAXI DRIVER: $14.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
Where's all the furniture?
I'll try to call Carman again.
Where are we gonna sleep?
Mum? What're we gonna do?
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
Okay, hop in, Lukey.
Hey, Mum, when do we get
to sleep in real beds?
(SIGHS)
Well, you got
the rest of your lives
to sleep in real beds, you know?
But it's just so boring.
(CHUCKLES)
Sometimes when I sleep
in a real bed
and I've got nothing to do,
I just...
(LAUGHING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Think about it.
Cowboys. Astronauts.
Knights in shining armor.
They don't need real beds. No.
Because they have
adventure beds.
Beds that say, "I don't know
what tomorrow's gonna bring,
"because my life
is an adventure."
And that's what this is.
Our exciting adventure.
Together.
I meet with Carman first thing
in the morning.
Almost out of the woods, darl.
I'll sort it out.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
G'day. I'm here for Carman
at nine o'clock.
- David, you made it!
- Oh, that's one way to put it.
Ah!
- How's Helen? And the kids?
- Oh, she's... They're tired.
We got in around midnight
last night, but look,
I hate to cut to the chase
but if we can get squared away
on the contract and the bonus
and a car.
We really need a car.
(CHUCKLES)
You remember Pierce, right?
(STUTTERS) Go ahead
and take a seat, David.
Day five of the epic test match,
Smallbones versus Smallbones,
with Smallbones
on the cusp of victory.
- You bet we are.
- (DOOR SHUTS)
Let's go,
World Cup for Australia!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Dad, this place is awesome!
We can play cricket
in the house!
You're back already?
That was quick.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
What happened?
(SIGHS)
He, uh, took a better deal.
His label got wind
of what we were doing
and they extended his contract.
(SIGHS)
Helen, I'll...
Groceries.
Take Daniel and Bec.
It's a long walk.
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
That's what got us
through Customs.
It's a miracle.
It's like some kind of sign
that we're supposed to be here.
(SIGHS)
I agreed to two years.
And come what may,
I am not gonna be another person
that breaks a promise to you.
(KISSES)
(SLOW INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
♪ Thank you, Lord,
for giving us food ♪
♪ Right where we are ♪
♪ Amen ♪
I know some of you are excited
to be here,
and others less so.
I for one, am absolutely
thrilled to be here.
- Oh, nice one, Joelsy.
- No worries, Bec.
HELEN: Thank you, Joel.
However you guys feel
about being here,
we completely understand.
But the fact is, we are here,
and we need to make it work.
And we need to make
some changes.
Starting with me and your dad.
We need to be honest with you,
because we need your help.
On my last tour back home,
I lost a lot of money.
Want us to help you find it?
It's gone now, darling.
Thank you, though.
- (SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
- And because of that,
no one would hire me
in Australia,
so I got a job here.
And this morning...
(SIGHS)
that job fell through.
Wait. So we're not going back?
Your dad and I believe
that this is where
we're supposed to be.
- So this isn't an adventure?
- HELEN: Oh, no, it is.
Every adventure has perils
and pitfalls.
And pirates.
Yeah, we've had a fair few
of those, haven't we?
So we have to be brave together.
And it's not enough for us
to just be here for Dad.
We have to be here
for each other as well.
And we need to pray, every day,
for everything that we need.
This is everything we have.
And sometimes it's gonna grow,
and sometimes it will shrink.
Rent, bills, groceries.
But it cannot be allowed
to disappear.
Can we pray now? I'll start.
God, I pray
that you will give us
everything that we need.
A job for Dad.
If it'll help, I wouldn't mind
having one, too.
- Same.
- Me, too.
- And we need food.
- And a car.
And furniture,
so we don't have to sleep
on the floor.
Not that I mind.
God knows your mind,
so you might as well
be honest, Benji.
- All right, all right.
- LUKE: You wanna pray, Dad?
God...
I don't even really know
where to start.
But I ask that you would show
Mum and me, all of us...
show us the way.
- Amen.
- CHILDREN: Amen.
HELEN: Come on.
(CONGREGATION SINGING
ALL TO JESUS)
Come on, come on,
rattle your dags.
♪ All to Thee,
my blessed Savior ♪
♪ I surrender all ♪
LUANNE: Please be seated.
- (INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
- LUANNE: So before we continue
our journey through the Psalms,
I'm gonna read you
some Sunday announcements.
Sorry. Excuse me.
LUANNE: There's a clothing
and a food drive
at the Metro Mission Center...
Sorry. Excuse me.
Taking clothing
and food donations.
And y'all, the youth group
gets back up and running
this Wednesday at 6:00 p.m.
And the homeschool
tutorial starts
a week from Monday at 9:00 a.m.
Talk to Kay Albright
if you're interested.
So would you please stand
for the reading of God's Word?
"I lift up my eyes
to the mountains.
"Where does my help come from?
"My help comes from the Lord,
"the Maker of Heaven and Earth.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
"Nashville Homeschool Tutorial."
Homeschooling? Darl.
Well, public school
already started.
So, you know,
maybe we just try it
for a semester
and see how it goes?
How y'all doin'?
Y'all must be new.
We'd have noticed you
before now,
- no offense.
- (HELEN AND DAVID CHUCKLE)
We do sort of stand out,
don't we? (CHUCKLES)
Are y'all from England?
Uh, Australia.
Australia. Wish I had an accent.
- Appreciate it.
- (CHUCKLING) Yeah.
Well, I'm Kay.
This is my husband, Jed.
- Helen.
- David.
- JED: Nice to meet you.
- G'day.
My name's Joshua,
but you can call me Josh.
(JED AND KAY CHUCKLE)
Well, it's good to know, Josh.
Are you guys visiting or?
- Oh, this is home...
- Two years.
Do you know anything about
the, um, homeschool tutorial?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, we've got two girls.
They just love it.
Are y'all thinking
of joining us?
Yeah, if there's space.
I mean, there are a fair
few of us, though.
(CHUCKLES) You don't say.
Tell you what, you need
any help signing up,
anything at all,
- you just give me a ring.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Well,
welcome to Nashville, y'all.
(HELEN SIGHS)
DAVID: We're in luck, boys.
(LAWNMOWER WHIRRING)
(LAWNMOWER STOPS)
Hey, Joely, Luke,
let's empty her out.
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
- STEVE: Hey, neighbor.
- G'day.
(CHUCKLES) That's quite a crew
you got there.
Yeah, proper cricket team.
(LAUGHS) Hey,
maybe when you all get done,
you could come do my place?
I'm not sure we're quite ready
to take this show on the road...
How much would you pay us?
(CRAZY BY SEAL PLAYING)
♪ A man decides
after 70 years ♪
♪ That what he goes there for ♪
(INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION)
♪ Is to unlock the door ♪
♪ While those around him
criticize and sleep ♪
♪ And through a fractal
on a breaking wall ♪
♪ I see you my friend ♪
♪ And touch your face again ♪
♪ Miracles will happen
as we trip ♪
(SIGHS)
♪ But we're never gonna
survive, unless ♪
♪ We get a little crazy ♪
♪ No we're never gonna
survive, unless ♪
♪ We are a little ♪
(SIGHS)
♪ Crazy... ♪
$87.80.
Could I just put
a couple of things back?
♪ And yet together
they were friends at school ♪
♪ Ohh, get it, get it,
get it, get it no no ♪
G'day, Smallbone residence.
Dave speaking.
Yeah.
Helen, we got another job!
Mum, how do you spell "cheap"?
- C-H-E...
- Why do you ask, Lukey?
I wanna ask God
to make things more cheap.
C-H-E-A...
♪ No no, never survive ♪
♪ Unless we get a little bit ♪
$93.81.
(CASH REGISTER BEEPING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
- Hey, Luke.
- Hey, Dad.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING
IN DISTANCE)
JAMES: (OVER PHONE)
Well, I'm glad you're all
finding your footing.
Some of us. Yeah.
No, all of you.
It may not be
the way you wanted,
but you're making your way.
The kids are chipping in.
Part of it makes me proud.
Part of it makes me sad.
Does it make them sad?
I'm not sure
they know any better.
(LAUGHS) They know enough.
And I think
they're onto something.
Any rate,
you have all my prayers.
Thanks. Thanks, Dad.
You'll pull through, son.
Chin up.
"If you can dream..."
"And not make dreams
your master..."
"You will be a man, my son."
Yeah. Good on ya.
- Love you.
- Love you, too.
Wow, this yard is huge.
So is the house.
(DANIEL GRUNTS)
Wait up.
(DOOR CREAKING)
G'day. Uh, David Smallbone
from Australia.
I've recently arrived
with my family.
Uh, we started a lawn care
and housecleaning business,
wondering if we could
be of service.
Gotta go.
The David Smallbone
from Australia
is the only David Smallbone
I know.
Eddie DeGarmo.
In the flesh.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
I, uh...
Wow.
Yeah. How did you, uh...
How'd you get here?
We walked, as usual.
From Australia?
It's a long story.
- I take it the tour went well.
- EDDIE: It did.
Y'all have a beautiful country.
Thanks very much.
Uh, well, look, congratulations.
Oh, we'll be off.
Great to see ya.
Come on, kids.
EDDIE: You want the gig or not?
(SOFT MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
JOEL: Thank you.
I never said it was ideal.
NANA: But you don't
have real jobs,
you don't even have a car.
Just come home.
It's not working over there.
Mum, I know you love me
and I appreciate your concern, truly.
But, these last two months,
I've just seen miracles.
Helen, it's time.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER, LAUGHTER)
HELEN: Oh, no, we wouldn't
want to impose.
Nonsense!
We'd love to have y'all.
Truth is, um,
we don't have a car
or any real way to, um,
get us all there.
Sure you do, hon.
Jed'll swing by
and pick you all up.
You ain't missing Thanksgiving.
This is America.
- (UPBEAT GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CHUCKLES)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
- (CHILDREN CHATTERING)
- Oh, hey, bud.
Mum says
we'll be out right away.
Sounds good.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CHILDREN CONTINUE CHATTERING)
Jed!
Hey, David. How ya doin'?
Uh, good. Good-good.
Getting there.
Jed, so sorry
to keep you waiting.
No, it's fine. I'm just...
I'll be right here.
We'll just be one more minute.
Grab your jackets.
LUKE: Everybody in the car!
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
- Just a little taste of home.
- Oh.
Jelly?
- Thanks a bunch.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure. Yes.
- Thanks so much!
- Thank you.
- Thanks heaps.
- Thank you so much.
- Oh, no problem.
"Vegemite"?
BEN: Wow, nice place!
REBECCA: Get out, little monkey.
It's like our house back home,
huh, Mum?
- Yes. It's lovely.
- JED: Thanks, y'all.
- BEN: What's your job?
- Ben, we don't...
No, no, it's fine.
I, I write songs.
JOEL: Oh, great!
Dad's in music, too.
Yeah. So I hear.
HELEN: Thank you.
LUKE: Whoa!
What's over here?
HELEN: Is it okay
that they just...
(CHUCKLING) Oh, no, I'm sorry.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
KAY: Happy Thanksgiving.
I'm so glad y'all could make it.
HELEN: Happy Day
of Thanksgiving.
- (HELEN CHUCKLES)
- Yeah, thanks for having us.
- Uh, I'll take your coats.
- Make yourselves at home.
There are snacks in the kitchen
and, kids,
you all can head upstairs
to the game room,
if you want or...
- CHILDREN: Game room?
- Be good.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, come on in.
Y'all are gonna leave here
fuller than a tick
on a coonhound.
Thanks very much.
(SIGHS)
JED: Our most loving Father,
we thank you
for our many blessings,
our dear friends, old and new.
We thank you for this
delicious feast before us.
- Amen.
- ALL: Amen.
♪ Thank you, Lord,
for giving us food ♪
SMALLBONES:
♪ Thank you, Lord ♪
♪ For giving us food ♪
♪ Thank you, Lord,
for giving us food ♪
♪ Right where we are, Amen ♪
♪ Hallelujah, praise the Lord ♪
REBECCA:
♪ Right where we are ♪
- (GUESTS APPLAUDING)
- CHILD: Amen.
Hey, you all right?
Seems like they could
use some help.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
That is the biggest chicken
I've ever seen.
It's no chicken, sweetie,
it's an ostrich.
So, Kay tells me
you're a promoter.
Oh, once upon a time, yeah.
You know someone
looking for one?
Well, I may know somebody
who should be.
Oh, darl, can't just throw her
to the wolves.
(SIGHS)
I wouldn't underestimate her...
or any of them.
JED: Thanks for coming.
- You have a good night.
- KAY: Good night.
(DOOR SHUTS)
Hey, thank you so much
for having us.
Our pleasure.
Yeah, I think the kids
are a bit knackered.
Could we trouble you
to give us a ride home?
Here ya go.
HELEN: Oh, Jed,
- we can't borrow your van.
- I mean...
Well, Kay and I had a chat,
and the way we see it,
it's yours now.
- I... Mate, that's kind...
- HELEN: Oh, no,
we don't have insurance.
(LAUGHS) Let 'em sue me.
I think God wants us
to give you the van.
We'll sort the rest out later.
(SLOW DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(HELEN CHUCKLING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
JOEL: Dad,
turn on the cassette player!
Turn on the radio!
REBECCA: Oh, yeah, yeah!
No, play that.
Play the cassette, please.
No, it's got a cassette player
and a CD player.
(RHYTHM OF MY HEART BY ROD
STEWART PLAYING OVER TAPE)
Happy Thanksgiving, darling.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You too, darl.
REBECCA:
♪ Oh, the rhythm of my heart ♪
♪ Is beating like a drum ♪
♪ With the words "I love you"
Rolling off my tongue ♪
♪ No, never will I roam
For I know my place is home ♪
♪ Where the ocean meets
the sky I'll be sailin' ♪
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
All right, there.
You've got this.
You'll be all right.
Just make it your own.
Hit it, boys.
(TAPE CLICKS)
(THAT'S WHAT LOVE IS FOR
BY AMY GRANT PLAYING)
♪ That's what love is for ♪
♪ To help us through it ♪
- ♪ That's what love... ♪
- All right, stop. Stop.
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
- What?
Sweetie, what's this?
What are you doing?
Oh.
Moving my hand.
Oh, well, just try to move it
more like a normal person.
I mean, just don't try so hard.
You know, relax.
Let's give it another go.
LUKE AND JOEL:
♪ That's what love is for ♪
♪ To help us through it ♪
♪ That's what love is for... ♪
All right.
That's really nice, boys.
- But that's... that's enough.
- (LAUGHING)
Let's give it another go.
- I want a record deal.
- So do I.
Yeah, well, get in line.
All right, from the top.
- (TAPE CLICKS)
- (MUSIC RESUMES PLAYING)
Just relax. Yeah. Yeah, no.
(EXHALES)
(GRUNTS)
♪ That's what love is for ♪
♪ To help us through it ♪
♪ That's what love is... ♪
DAVID: Yeah,
I don't know what it is.
When she sings and thinks
no one's watching, she shines.
But then in those rehearsals,
the spark's just...
It's just gone.
Well, it can't be easy,
performing under critical eyes.
It's only gonna get harder
from here, darling.
Just give her time.
Another thing we can't afford.
JOEL: Mum! Mum!
HELEN: What's this?
Oh.
Christmas list.
(SIGHS) Money's tight, boys.
Santa doesn't care
that we're poor.
True.
But because we moved,
he might not know where we live.
What? You didn't tell him?
Why didn't you tell him
we moved?
- That's enough, Joel.
- We have to pray.
DAVID: It doesn't
work like that.
We've prayed
for everything else.
Why can't we pray for this?
Look.
We promised
to be honest with you.
It's time you knew. (SIGHS)
- There's...
- Yes, it's time you knew
what Mum wants for Christmas.
A washing machine and a dryer.
(HELEN CHUCKLES)
- Who wants to pray?
- I will.
Jesus, I bet you
and St. Nick are good friends.
So if you could
give him our address,
we'd be very glad.
And please give Mum
a washer and dryer.
- Amen.
Amen. Okay, take that
and get the others to write
what they want, as well, okay?
JOEL AND LUKE: Guys,
Santa needs to know
what you want for Christmas!
I'm sorry, David.
I just couldn't.
If not now then when, darl?
Christmas morning?
(SIGHS)
Ooh!
It's freezing.
Those wintery Christmas carols
now make a lot more sense.
Well, I can't imagine
Christmas in the summer.
- That seems so wrong.
- (BOTH CHUCKLE)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS)
(KAY CHUCKLES)
They always have the funniest
little knickknacks
to put in all the stockings.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
May I?
Oh, honey, you're, uh,
you're not gonna find
much of this here.
Yeah, I see that.
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
DAVID: Grab a spoon.
Go and get the cream.
HELEN: Oh, yeah, get the cream.
(GRUNTS) Can he get it?
(CHILDREN EXCLAIMING)
CHILDREN: Yeah!
DAVID: On the cookie,
can he land it?
BEN: Come on, Joshie!
DAVID: Yes,
all right, all right.
- You're doing great.
- DANIEL: Thank you.
(CHILDREN AND DAVID EXCLAIMING)
DAVID: Danny, put the sprinkles
- on the cookie!
- (DOORBELL RINGS)
JOEL: Oh, I'll get it.
- LUKE: I'll come, too.
- Who could that be?
I don't know.
Maybe it's carolers.
They do that in America.
BOYS: Santa!
- Ho, ho, ho! Merry Christmas.
- (CHILDREN EXCLAIMING)
- Merry Christmas.
- Santa! Look, Dad, it's Santa!
MAN: Back at ya, bud.
- CHILD: Presents!
- Merry Christmas, Smallbones.
Joy to the world, y'all.
(CHUCKLES)
CONGREGANTS: ♪ We wish
you a merry Christmas ♪
♪ We wish you
a merry Christmas ♪
♪ And a happy new year ♪
A washer!
♪ To you and your kin ♪
♪ Good tidings for Christmas
And a happy new year ♪
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Thank you, Jed.
No, man, Kay's the one who...
Well, the church and Santa,
of course.
What did I tell you, Mum?
CONGREGANTS:
♪ Hark the herald angels sing ♪
♪ Glory to the newborn king ♪
♪ Peace on earth
and mercy mild ♪
♪ God and sinners reconciled ♪
♪ Joyful all ye nations rise ♪
♪ Join the triumph
of the skies ♪
♪ With angelic... ♪
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(WASHING MACHINE WHIRRING)
(WASHING MACHINE BEEPS)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
David, it's time.
What's that, darl?
HELEN: David.
Are you sure?
Right.
Kids, Mum's gonna have the baby.
CHILDREN: Now? What?
(EXCITED CHATTER)
HELEN: Come say goodbye.
We'll be back
in a couple of days.
(GROANING IN PAIN)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- DOCTOR TANAKA: Okay, Helen...
- Something feels different.
DOCTOR TANAKA: Take a deep
breath and one more push.
Okay, you can do this.
- You've got this.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
Ready? You've got this, okay?
(GROANING IN PAIN)
(CONTINUES GROANING IN PAIN)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BABY CRYING)
(CRYING)
Congratulations,
it's a beautiful baby girl.
Oh! Hi, baby!
Oh!
(DAVID KISSES)
It's little American girl.
(LAUGHS)
She looks
true-blue Aussie to me.
You can tell by her accent.
- Little Elizabeth.
- (KISSES)
Hi, little Libby.
DAVID: Now we have bookends.
Two girls.
(HELEN CHUCKLES, SNIFFLES)
Am I okay?
- You did great. (KISSES)
- Oh, David.
DOCTOR TANAKA: Helen,
we need to clear the placenta.
One more push, okay?
(HELEN INHALES, GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
- Helen. Darling.
- No.
- What's going on?
- David.
- DAVID: What's happening?
What's wrong? What's wrong?
(TENSE MUSIC PLAYING)
(BABY CRYING)
(IMPERCEPTIBLE)
Stay with me. Stay with me.
Hey. Don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
DAVID: Helen.
Darling.
Where's Libby?
Oh, she's fine. The baby's fine.
What?
The, uh, doctor was worried
about the bleeding.
She wants you
to stay a few days to rest.
Oh, no. I can't. We can't stay
- 'cause of the cost.
- Hey, don't worry about it.
I'm gonna be all right.
Sweetie, don't worry about it.
We've got a healthy,
beautiful baby girl.
- (CHUCKLES)
- That's all that matters.
- I'm so sorry.
- Oh, darl.
- I'm so sorry. (SOBS)
- Hey. No. Listen to me.
I'll take care of it. I promise.
I'll sort it out.
- You just rest.
- Okay.
(KISSES)
- I love you.
DAVID: Look, I'd pay it all
if I could, but I can't.
We don't have insurance yet
and...
WOMAN: Mr. Smallbone,
refusal to pay...
DAVID: Oh, look,
I'm not refusing to pay.
Just asking you to let me pay
what I actually can.
Please.
(SIGHS)
Well, let's look
at payment options.
What can you pay today?
I...
I could do $200 a month.
How about $250 a month
for a year?
So, $3,000 total?
And we'll consider it settled.
I think I can manage that.
I'll come through.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
All right.
Just give me a second, here.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
- WOMAN: Mm-hmm.
- (KEYBOARD CLACKING)
- (EXHALES)
- (SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
WOMAN: Oh.
That's weird.
Says here
it's been paid in full.
(WOMAN CHUCKLES)
By who?
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Doesn't say.
Looks like you have
a guardian angel.
(SIGHS)
CHILDREN: Mum! Mum!
(HELEN AND CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Oh, gentle, gentle, Mummy.
(CHUCKLES)
Missed you guys.
- Hi. You doing okay?
- Yeah, I'm good.
DAVID: Dad's here, too.
HELEN: Do you wanna
meet your sister?
Oh, she's so cute.
What's her name?
HELEN: Elizabeth.
Libby, for short.
DAVID: All right, it's cold.
- Let's get everyone inside.
- KAY: Yeah, let's get inside.
- Can I take her?
- HELEN: Okay. Thank you.
KAY: How are you, guys?
REBECCA: You feeling okay?
HELEN: Yeah, good.
JED: Need a hand?
I can manage.
So glad Helen's okay.
The baby, too.
- Yeah.
- Thank God.
Hey, your kids are just great.
I mean, what a joy.
Kay and I,
we just love 'em to death.
They all think
you're just grand.
A real hero.
- Here, let me help you.
- I said I can manage.
You okay?
I know you paid the bill.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
- And it's too much.
- Oh, look...
I told her I'd take care of it.
I promised.
I thought I'd lost her, Jed.
Hey, I'm sorry.
Kay and I,
we're just trying to help.
You know, it's not just that
you paid the bill.
It's that you gave them double.
I had them down to $3,000.
I'd finally done
something worthwhile,
and you didn't even
give me the chance.
You just threw money at it!
You throw money at everything.
Look, if you wanna help us,
please just back off.
You gotta back off.
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(THAT'S WHAT LOVE IS FOR
BY AMY GRANT PLAYING)
REBECCA:
♪ That's what love is for ♪
♪ To help us through it ♪
♪ Nothing else can do it... ♪
MAN: Very nice.
Miss Smallbone, thanks.
We'll let you know.
JAMES: (OVER PHONE)
Yeah, forget other folks.
I'm talking to you.
You'll always be my favorite
granddaughter named Rebecca.
- Yeah. Thanks, Grandpa James.
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
God makes everything beautiful
in its time.
Yeah. Right.
Oh, here's Dad.
I love you, very much.
- And I, you.
- (SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
DAVID: All right, Dad,
we'll let you go.
- She's a special one, David.
- DAVID: Yeah, I know.
Trick is getting other folks
to see it.
Nothing seems to be working.
MAN: I'm just staying what
everyone's gonna be thinking.
Does anybody really care
what a 16-year-old girl
thinks about life?
Or God?
Or anything else,
for that matter?
I know what I believe, sir.
Sure.
Come back when you look like it.
I don't think we will.
LUKE: Be with Bec
at her auditions.
Help her to sing better,
and fix her hands
so she can get a record deal.
BEN: Please help us make money,
even in the winter...
Be with Dad
as he looks for another job.
DAVID: I promise
I'll work harder than anyone.
I have no doubt you would.
But with these
visa restrictions, I don't...
Sorry, I can't be more help.
It's all right.
You need your rest.
Yeah.
JAMES: (OVER PHONE)
It's fine eyeing the horizon,
just don't miss
what's right in front of you.
DAVID: Easy for you to say.
I'm over here
in the thick of it,
trying to figure out
right-side up
- from upside-down.
- (JAMES SIGHS)
I only meant,
"If you can dream..."
DAVID: I'm not saying
the poem, Dad.
Appreciate the sentiment
but that's all it is,
is just sentiment.
Have fun on your date.
All right, let's go play.
REBECCA:
The more I think about it,
the more I wonder if he's right.
Maybe I'm not meant to sing.
Or maybe you're not meant
to sing other people's songs.
I'm not a songwriter.
Bec, you have been given
a beautiful voice.
And you have a good heart.
You could do anything.
Just make sure
it's the real you that does it.
Dad, I wrote a song.
Thought maybe we could try it
at the next audition.
Oh, that's great, honey.
Let's take it
one step at a time. (KISSES)
JAMES: (OVER PHONE) David,
just don't make
the same mistake I did.
Took me too long to realize...
Look, I gotta go.
Son, your family,
they're not in the way.
They are the way.
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC CONTINUES)
Yeah.
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
EDDIE: Oh, but you can't take
that stuff seriously, dude.
That's just Kevin.
He's a loose cannon.
I told you that.
Uh-huh.
I understand that.
Yeah.
Um, when you're all done here,
Susan will get you squared away.
Cash, right?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
Huh?
No, no, just talking
to the cleaning guy.
No, I'm just saying,
don't take it personally,
that's all.
(SIGHS)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
REBECCA: You know, Mr. DeGarmo
started a record label.
HELEN: Really?
REBECCA: Yeah.
HELEN: Did you know that, David?
I did.
Mummy, I want a little Band-Aid.
Oh, you're not bleeding, darling.
But it stings.
Okay. Well, a Band-Aid is not
gonna make it not sting. Okay?
Here. (KISSES) All better. Okay?
- Okay.
- (CHILDREN CHATTERING)
You never told me
that about Eddie.
- Oh, no?
- JOEL: Mum, I'm hungry.
HELEN: Yeah, well,
dinner's nearly ready.
Why don't you take the bowls,
set the table.
- Ramen again?
- HELEN: Yes. Bowls, Joel.
And, Ben,
can you get the cutlery?
Danny, you can help as well.
No, I'd have remembered
you telling me
something like that.
That's incredible. I mean,
right under our noses
this whole time.
Don't you think
that's incredible, David?
Mum, my robot needs batteries.
It's broken, Luke.
You'll just have to pretend, darling.
I thought we could ask him
for an audition,
- since he's a friend.
- Yeah, I don't see why not.
I don't think it's a good idea.
- Mum, please.
- There's no batteries, Luke.
Okay, you just go
and sit at the table.
Why isn't it a good idea?
Look. We've got
the Word Records audition.
I say we focus on that.
I feel good about it.
Yeah, but we felt good
about other ones, too, so,
if it doesn't work out, I just
thought that Mr. DeGarmo...
I don't think
it's the right fit.
Well, (SIGHS) beggars can't
be choosers, David.
We're not all beggars, Helen.
What is that supposed to mean?
It means I know this business.
And I'm not begging Eddie
or anyone.
Yeah, but I'm not asking you
to beg, Dad.
I just thought we could talk
to him since he's a friend
- and not just give up.
- He's not your friend.
But why not just give it a go.
I don't understand
- why you won't even try...
- Because you're his maid!
(CHILDREN STOP CHATTERING)
(SIGHS)
You're just his maid, Bec.
That's all you are to him.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
Bec. Look, I only meant...
You bite her head off
for trying.
You're being too hard on her.
Compared to what, Helen?
Compared to you?
I wanted to protect her
from this,
but you pushed for it.
So now someone's gotta teach her
and all of them to face facts.
You don't need to tell me
that I'm a bad mum
'cause I already feel like
I'm failing them every day.
No one thinks you're a bad mum.
Everyone knows
who the real failure is.
- Oh, such pride.
- DAVID: Oh!
- So much pride!
- DAVID: Yeah, right.
So much pride
that I just scrubbed
Eddie DeGarmo's toilet.
But, hey, if that's
not degrading enough,
now I have to go down
on bended knee
asking for a record deal?
- She just wants an audition.
- That's not the point.
I'm trying to protect her,
to spare her
- from humiliation.
- (CHUCKLES)
But that means nothing to you.
It's nothing for you
to go begging
for presents or furniture.
What was I supposed to do,
- just turn them away?
- Oh, right.
Let Christmas come
and go to spare you?
They just magically showed up
in our yard...
Do you pay attention
to anyone but yourself?
Gifts in hand.
Another miracle.
It was a miracle. It was!
No, it wasn't lightning
from the sky.
It was an answered prayer.
And would it kill you
to be grateful?
- I was grateful! I was!
- Oh, yes.
DAVID: Am I not allowed to feel
more than one thing
at the same time?
That's one thing
we don't allow in our house,
is room for you
and your feelings.
They just showed up
with their pity
and their judgment.
- No one is judging us.
- They're judging me, Helen!
You are not protecting her.
You're not protecting
any of them.
You're protecting your pride.
And it's holding them back.
Just because
you had your dreams dashed
doesn't mean
I'm gonna stand here
and let you crush theirs.
You think I'm too hard on you?
- Bec, do you?
- HELEN: David.
No. She needs to hear
what I wish to God
someone had told me.
People in this industry,
they're not your friends.
They do not care about you
or what happens to you.
- David.
- They only care about
what you can do for them.
And it's not enough.
It will never be enough.
- You will never be enough!
- David! Stop it! Get out.
You need to leave. Leave!
(REBECCA SOBBING)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(REBECCA CONTINUES SOBBING)
♪ The wind is moving
but I am standing still ♪
♪ A life of pages
waiting to be filled ♪
♪ A heart that's hopeful
A head that's full of dreams ♪
♪ But this becoming is harder
than it seems ♪
♪ It feels like
I'm looking for a reason ♪
♪ Roaming through the night ♪
♪ To find my place
in this world ♪
♪ My place in this world ♪
♪ Not a lot to lean on ♪
♪ I need your light
to help me find ♪
♪ My place in this world ♪
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(TENSE MUSIC SWELLS, FADES)
We see a lot of potential
here, Rebecca.
With the right direction
and the right team,
we think that we might
be looking
at the next Amy Grant.
REBECCA: Oh.
Thanks heaps. (CHUCKLES)
- And the accent.
- It's so cute.
- The accent, it... (LAUGHS)
- It's adorable.
It's so charming.
(MIMICKING AUSTRALIAN ACCENT)
"That's not a knife."
- Yes. Yes. (LAUGHS)
- "Now that's a knife." Right?
- Crocodile Dundee.
- Oh, yes!
It's really, really good. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
So, (CLEARS THROAT) here it is.
We are prepared to offer you
a development deal.
SANDY: Yes, you cut five tracks
for an advance of $10,000.
And if all goes well
and we think it will,
we're looking at a full record.
- (SANDY CHUCKLES)
- (CHUCKLES)
SANDY: She doesn't believe it.
Did she hear me?
- Yeah, nah...
- SANDY: Full record. (LAUGHS)
(IT AIN'T OVER 'TIL IT'S OVER
BY LENNY KRAVITZ PLAYING)
DAVID: All right,
three cheers for Bec.
- Hip! Hip!
- ALL: Hurray!
DAVID: Hip! Hip!
ALL: Hurray!
DAVID: Here's for the lady
of the hour.
Thank you so much.
DAVID: Hey.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
Ah!
Record deal!
(ALL SCREAM)
♪ So many tears I've cried ♪
♪ So much pain inside ♪
♪ Baby, it ain't over
'til it's over ♪
♪ So many gears we tried ♪
♪ To keep our love alive ♪
♪ But, baby,
it ain't over 'til it's over ♪
- (MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
- (TELEPHONE RINGING)
(BABY CRYING)
Hello?
NANA: David? (SOBBING)
Nana. You all right?
(NANA SIGHS)
I, I'll, I'll put Helen on.
No, David, no.
I'm calling for you.
It's James, your dad.
He's gone.
What do you mean he's gone?
He...
He passed away.
I'm so sorry, David.
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(SNIFFLES)
DAVID: I know we talked about
sending the advance next week,
but I was wondering
if there's any chance
we could speed things along.
Uh...
Something's come up.
I've gotta get back
to Australia.
We don't need the full amount...
MATT: Gotta be honest
with you, David.
Sandy and I got to talking
and Rebecca's great.
We think she has
a bright future.
We agree on that.
We just need to give it
some time on our end,
maybe we talk again
in a year or two
- when she's further along.
- Uh...
She's a quick learner.
She's come such a long way
in a short amount of time.
You've seen she's a natural.
Yeah. Yeah. It's...
It's just not the right time.
I can work with her.
- Let me work with her.
- David, what's the matter?
Look, just give us a chance.
I know she's green.
But she's... she's got a gift.
Whatever's wrong we can fix it.
Yeah, that's not gonna
work for us.
Is this because of me?
- Matt?
- It's just a big risk.
Matt, please. Don't do this.
Don't do this to her.
I'm begging you.
I... I can step away.
I can take it.
Just don't do this
to my little girl.
Man, she's just a kid.
David, it's business.
You know that.
She may as well know it, too.
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(SOBBING)
AUTOMATED VOICE:
If you'd like to make a call,
hang up and try again.
Hang up and then
dial your operator.
(SNIFFLES)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
David.
(DAVID SCREAMS, SOBS)
(HELEN SOBBING)
(DAVID CONTINUES SOBBING)
- (MUSIC FADES OUT)
- (CRYING)
(DAVID CONTINUES SOBBING)
(SHE BELIEVES IN ME BY
FOR KING AND COUNTRY PLAYING)
♪ Clouds hanging lower ♪
♪ Raining, it's cold out now ♪
♪ Watching my breath
escape me ♪
♪ Feeling a life fall ♪
♪ Here in the night calling ♪
♪ The weight of the world
has found me ♪
♪ But she believes in me ♪
♪ She believes in me ♪
NANA: Come on, Helen,
it's time.
I'll call your brothers.
We'll pool finances together
and cover the fares.
David really wants to be there
to bury James,
so maybe
if you could just cover him.
No, Helen, you all come home.
For good.
Come home.
- I'll call you back, Mum.
- Helen...
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
♪ She believes in me ♪
Mummy, I'm hungry.
Okay.
David.
There's no food.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
And we're almost out of money.
What kind of man am I?
What kind of husband?
Or father?
Or son?
- I can't even bury my own dad.
- (HELEN SNIFFLES)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(SIGHS)
BEN: Do you have an ace?
LUKE: Go fish.
- Do you have a four?
- Kids, grab your jackets.
BEN: Why?
DANIEL: Where're we going?
Out. Let's go, guys. Let's go.
(DANIEL SIGHS)
♪ You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
♪ You make everything ♪
JOEL AND LUKE:
♪ Everything new ♪
♪ In its time, in Your time ♪
Boys, not now.
(BOYS STOP SINGING)
(SIGHS)
BEN: Look, a playground!
JOEL: Whoa! (CHUCKLES)
Mum, can we pull over, please?
Mum, Mum, Mum, pull over.
- Please Mum! Please, Mum!
- Can we go, please, Mum?
(CHILDREN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
All right, all right!
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Go on, darling.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING, LAUGHING)
REBECCA: All right,
who's the captain?
JOEL: Me!
DANIEL: Oh, we can't all
be the captain!
- Starboard side!
- Look ahead!
- JOEL: I'm going down!
- (MIMICKING GUNSHOTS)
REBECCA: I need backup!
We've gotta take cover.
Mum, come on! Up here!
Fire as you bear!
Fire!
- Fire at the...
- Four points to starboard!
- Uh, which way is that?
- Uh, right, right! I think.
There! There it is, there it is!
What? Where?
The pirates' castle!
They're in there, over there!
I thought I smelled pirates.
What d'ya think,
Lieutenant Joshie?
- Let's get 'em.
- Yeah.
Fire when ready, Captain Benji.
Fire!
ALL: Fire!
Now what?
Let's go!
CHILDREN: Abandon! Abandon!
(HELEN AND CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
HELEN: All right, all right.
Before we attack,
who's got their torch?
I've got mine.
There's one thing left to do.
What? What is it?
We burn the ships. All of them.
- Even ours?
- How do we get back?
We don't.
It's gonna be dangerous
and scary,
and it's gonna be hard.
It's gonna be so hard
that you'll wanna go back.
But if you know that
you can go back, you will.
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
And giving up, giving in,
it's not an option.
We've gotta
fight our way forward.
We have to win.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
(INHALES)
(GRUNTS)
(CHILDREN GRUNTING)
(SOFT DRAMATIC MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
(FIRE CRACKLING)
♪ You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
everything new ♪
What is it that you're singing?
That's Bec's song.
You wrote a song, Bec?
Can I hear it?
REBECCA:
♪ You make everything ♪
♪ Everything beautiful ♪
♪ You make everything,
everything new ♪
everything beautiful ♪
♪ In its time, in Your time ♪
♪ It's beautiful ♪
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(WHISPERS) She wrote that.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
(IN NORMAL VOICE) Our kids
have come all this way.
They gave up everything,
and they're still happy.
Because they believe in us.
And they believe in you.
They just believe.
It's time for you
to believe, too.
Please.
(SNIFFLES)
(HELEN CRYING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
Dad! Dad!
Boys...
I've acted like a fool.
Can you forgive me?
Yeah, of course, Dad.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Helen.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
Becca...
(SIGHS) I lost sight
of what it's all about...
of who it's all about.
But you never did.
You're a beautiful singer.
But you're an even
more beautiful person.
You don't have
to give music another go,
and you certainly don't have
to do it with me.
But I need you to know
that I'm honored to be your dad.
And that I'm sorry.
(REBECCA CRYING)
(SOMBER INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
I'm sorry.
(KISSES)
REBECCA: I, um...
I do wanna try again.
And even if you don't, um,
manage me,
it helps to have family
in your corner.
If I had it my way,
I'd have you all there,
all the time.
- EDDIE: (OVER PHONE) Hello.
- Eddie DeGarmo,
David Smallbone. From Australia.
The David Smallbone
from Australia
is the only David Smallbone
I know.
(EXHILARATING MUSIC PLAYING)
So hit rewind.
And that will take you
to your next clip.
Whoa!
You're gonna sing harmonies
on the chorus,
and, uh, hey,
share this mic, right?
What? With Luke?
- Yeah, Joel, for Rebecca.
- And Jesus.
When you put it like that.
Good on ya, Joely.
Waiting in the wings
and stuck with you.
Story of my life.
Ah. Hey, Dad,
ready for sound check?
We're not gonna
use a track this time.
Why not?
You need to sing your own song.
Look, all this time,
I told you to trust me.
It's high time I trusted you.
Uh, I can't.
I've got no background music.
Yeah, you do.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING)
I called for help.
REBECCA: Thank you.
(DAVID SIGHS)
Dad kept trying to tell me.
And I didn't listen.
Hey, he knew you loved him.
He knows still.
Oh, darl, I wasted so much time,
chasing so many things,
and you were right here
the whole time.
I'm so sorry for missing you
and the kids.
And all the miracles.
But the greatest miracle is you.
(HELEN CHUCKLES)
That you love me.
That you're still here.
Well, you promised adventure
and you delivered.
(SIGHS)
- Eddie. How you going?
- Good, man, good.
Producing partner here,
Greg Ham.
David Smallbone.
- A pleasure.
- Uh, shall we?
Please.
Gentlemen,
without, uh, further ado,
Rebecca Jean Smallbone.
(PLAYING PIANO)
♪ Grant me serenity
to accept things ♪
♪ The things I cannot change ♪
♪ Grant me the courage, Lord
To change what I can ♪
♪ Wisdom to know
the difference ♪
♪ In my weakness
You can shine ♪
♪ In Your strength I can fly ♪
♪ And You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
♪ You make everything,
everything new ♪
♪ And You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
♪ In its time, in Your time ♪
♪ It's beautiful ♪
(SWITCH CLICKS)
REBECCA: ♪ Grant me serenity,
Lord, and patience ♪
♪ For things will take time ♪
♪ Grant me freedom
to walk a new path ♪
♪ And let me feel Your love ♪
♪ In my weakness
You can shine ♪
♪ In Your strength I can fly ♪
♪ And You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
♪ You make everything,
everything new ♪
everything beautiful ♪
♪ In its time, in Your time ♪
♪ It's beautiful ♪
♪ Lifting open hands
to You my Savior ♪
♪ Beautify my soul ♪
♪ Knowing You redeem my pain
and failure ♪
♪ Purify my soul ♪
♪ Beautify my soul ♪
♪ And You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
♪ You make everything,
everything new ♪
♪ And You make everything,
everything beautiful ♪
♪ In its time, in Your time ♪
♪ It's beautiful ♪
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(LUKE AND JOEL APPLAUDING)
Wow.
Becca, that was, uh,
that was good.
Thank you, sir.
But gotta be honest.
Not just looking
for another voice.
I love to sing.
And, if it can help other people
find what God's given me
and my family,
then I'll do it,
with all my heart.
- (EDDIE SIGHS)
- (INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Well, (SIGHS) Rebecca,
it pains me to say this
but, um, I'm gonna have
to look for someone else...
to clean my house.
- Welcome to Forefront Records.
- (GASPS)
(HELEN AND REBECCA LAUGHING)
DAVID: Well done.
Just, just one condition.
Yeah, no, I've got one as well.
Oh, well, ladies first.
I want Dad to manage me.
Done. (CHUCKLES)
I thought that was a given.
He's the hardest-working guy
I know.
Now here's my stipulation.
It's the name, Smallbone.
Hey, what's the matter with it?
All right. All right.
How you feel about
"Rebecca St. John"?
Well, you got something
better, I'm all ears.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(BRAKES HISSING)
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
- (KISSES) Love you.
- Love you.
Ready, Joshie?
I'm so proud of you.
- Grandpa James would be, too.
- DAVID: Well, g'day, everyone.
It's, uh,
David Smallbone here...
You know, Bec...
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
I always believed
that you could do
anything you set out to do.
And I knew that you could do it
without losing your soul.
And whatever your dream is,
I know you're going
to achieve it.
My dream is to be like you.
It always has been.
You're my hero, Mum.
JOSHUA: (OVER MICROPHONE)
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome, my big sister,
Rebecca St. James.
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(UNSUNG HERO
BY FOR KING & COUNTRY PLAYING)
♪ Once upon a time,
you were 25 ♪
♪ Walking up the aisle ♪
♪ You made the promise
of your life ♪
♪ Blinked twice
and you were 29 ♪
♪ Singing lullabies ♪
♪ And I looked up at you
for the first time ♪
♪ Words fall short
but I am sure ♪
♪ There'll never be ♪
♪ Anyone like you, you're ♪
♪ You're strong
like your father ♪
♪ Even when you are scared ♪
♪ When I was in trouble
You never left me there ♪
♪ And you love
like your mother ♪
♪ Like there's nothing
to lose ♪
♪ You're an unsung hero ♪
♪ So I'll sing this song
for you ♪
♪ Woke up, I was 21 ♪
♪ And I fell in love ♪
♪ Remember how
I told you that I'd ♪
♪ Searched the world
and I found the girl ♪
♪ And oh,
how she reminds me of you ♪
♪ You're strong
like your father ♪
♪ Even when you are scared ♪
♪ When I was in trouble
You never left me there ♪
♪ And you love
like your mother ♪
♪ Like there's nothing
to lose ♪
♪ You're an unsung hero ♪
♪ So I'll sing this song
for you ♪
♪ For all the times
I fell down ♪
♪ You showed me how to stand ♪
♪ And when we crossed
the ocean ♪
♪ You were my safe place
to land ♪
♪ Been on a thousand stages ♪
♪ But when it's all
said and done ♪
♪ I hope I make you proud of
Of the man that I've become ♪
♪ To be strong like my father
Even when I am scared ♪
♪ And when someone's
in trouble ♪
♪ I'll never leave them there ♪
♪ And I'll love
like my mother ♪
♪ Like there's
nothing to lose ♪
♪ You're my unsung hero ♪
♪ And I sing this song
for you ♪
(HARMONY BY SLEEPING AT LAST
AND FOR KING & COUNTRY PLAYS)
♪ Just the way
that you taught us ♪
♪ Sing our songs,
our melodies ♪
♪ In harmony ♪
♪ Just the way
that you taught us ♪
♪ Sing our songs,
our melodies ♪
♪ In harmony ♪
♪ Just the way
that you taught us now ♪
that you taught us ♪
(MUSIC FADES OUT)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC FADES OUT)